白 令 海
太平洋沿岸最北的边缘海
北纬58°31'00.8",西经176°13'12.6"
2月29日 俄东部标准时间 12时01分
任务报告
Mission Report.
K599俄联邦潜艇 塞瓦斯托波尔号
Russian Federation submarine K599 Sevastopol.
行动代号:马蹄铁
Operation: Podkova.
第74天
Day 74.
我们正在测试的自主学习防御系统
The active learning defense system we are testing…
依然毫无瑕疵地运行着
…continues to operate flawlessly.
甚至可以说是
One might even say…
奇迹般地运行着
…miraculously.
我们正在通过航位推测法 在北极冰层下航行
We are navigating under the Arctic ice cap by dead reckoning
并且再有五天就到家了
and five days from home.
在两万五千海里的航行过程中
After 25,000 nautical miles,
塞瓦斯托波尔号刻意接近了 世界各国的海军力量
the Sevastopol has deliberately approached every navy in the world
并且成功地避开了所有侦查
and remained completely undetected.
马蹄铁的反声波隐形能力 已经超出了所有人的预期
The Podkova's stealth capability has exceeded all expectations.
此刻我们手里掌握着这世上最尖端的
We are at this moment the state of the art
战争科技
of war.
这是人类有史以来
The most fearsome killing machine
最可怕的杀人机器
ever devised by man.
想找到我们就好比大海捞针
And we are impossible to find.
舰长 发现目标 代号S83
Captain, we have a submerged contact, designated Semyon-83,
是一艘美国弗吉尼亚级核潜艇
exhibiting tonals of a US Virginia-class submarine.
方位130°正朝我们逼近
Bearing 130°, drawing forward.
值班长注意 准备进入战斗状态
Chief of the Watch, man battle stations silently.
值更军官 汇报潜艇情况
Officer of the Deck, ship status?
船深50米 距离海底72米
Ship's depth, 50 meters. Bottom, 72 meters.
距离海面冰冠21米
Clearance to the ice canopy, 21 meters.
-距深海还有多远 -2公里
-Distance to deep water? -Two kilometers.
六分钟后抵达阿留申海底断崖
Aleutian Precipice in six minutes.
机动调整航向 舵手 左转舵15度
Ranging maneuver. Helm, left 15 degrees rudder.
保持航向100°
Steady course 100°.
以标准速度匀速上升
Come up easy on a standard bell.
-指挥权移交舰长 -收到指令
-Captain has the conn. -Helm, aye!
方位角调整到100°
Coming to course 100°.
稳定航向 100°
Steady on course 100°.
武器官 射程
Weapons Officer, range?
正在锁定目标 射击瞄准距离一万五千米
Firing solution is tracking at a distance of 15,000 meters.
长官 这个距离说不通 声呐信号怎么会这么清晰
Sir, that doesn't make sense. Tonals this loud and clear?
目标一定在更近的位置
He must be closer than that.
舰长 射击瞄准距离突然缩短 变成一万米了
Captain, firing solution just did a step change to 10,000 meters.
没有潜艇会这么快
Nothing moves that fast.
所有数据匹配 这是真实距离
All solutions are matching. The range is true.
舵手 右满舵 转向270°
Helm, right full rudder to course 270°.
右满舵270° 收到
Course 270°, aye.
我们避开目标 直接去深水区
We'll just walk away and head for deep water.
目标转向160°
Contact bearing 160°.
对方瞬间完成了变向
Bearing rate zero?
目标在那儿 又和我们一起转向了
He's there, turning with us again.
它能看到我们
He can see us.
这不可能 我们是隐形的
Impossible. We're invisible.
武器官 诊断声呐和作战系统程序 一定出问题了
Weapons, run diagnostics on sonar and fire control. Something isn't right.
长官 目标的鱼雷管道开始蓄水了
Sir, he's flooding his torpedo tubes!
鱼雷舱 这里是控制室 填装所有发射管道
Torpedo room, conn. Load all torpedo tubes.
是 长官
Aye, sir.
-仔细检查 -船前完毕
-Check clear! -Forward clear!
-船尾完毕 可以填装 -开始填装
-Aft clear! Ram torpedo! -Ramming!
所有鱼雷填装完毕
Torpedo tubes loaded.
目标已开启外侧舱门
He's opened outer doors!
武器官 一到四号管道蓄水 打开外侧舱门
Weapons, flood tubes one through four and open outer doors.
二号管道输入发射参数
Enter firing solution into tube two.
是 舰长 二号管道准备随时发射
Aye, Captain. Making tube two ready in all respects.
舰长 目标在挑衅我们
Captain, he's provoking us.
他在找借口把我们炸出水面
He wants an excuse to blow us out of the water.
发现敌方鱼雷 方位角200° 距离一千米 还在加速
Enemy torpedo in the water, bearing 200°. 1,000 meters and accelerating.
舵手 左满舵 别管一切 全速前进
Helm, left full rudder, all ahead flank cavitate.
收到 左满舵 已开启全速前进模式
My rudder is left full. Answering all ahead flank cavitate.
-启动反打击措施 -反打击措施启动
-Launch countermeasures. -Launching countermeasures.
-发射二号管道 -二号管道发射
-Fire tube two. -Firing tube two.
鱼雷已发射 高速运行中
Our torpedo is away. Running hot.
敌方鱼雷还在逼近 距离我们800米
Enemy torpedo still homing, range 800 meters.
他绕开了我们的反打击措施
He's blown through our countermeasures.
-舵手 右满舵 -收到 长官 右满舵
-Helm, right full rudder. -Right full. Aye, sir!
还有600米
600 meters.
下潜官待命 准备清空所有紧急压载舱
Diving Officer, stand by to emergency blow all main ballast tanks.
还有400米
400 meters.
值班长 准备拉响碰撞警报
Chief of the Watch, stand by the collision alarm.
只剩200米了
200 meters.
我是舰长 所有船员准备迎接打击
This is the captain. All hands brace for impact.
敌方鱼雷抵达倒计时
Enemy torpedo impact in…
五 四
five… four…
三 二
three… two…
一
one.
命中
Impact!
-到底怎么回事 -鱼雷不见了
-What just happened? -It's gone.
-它没击中 -不
-It missed us? -No.
它消失了 就像从没出现过一样
It vanished like it was never there.
声呐官 敌方舰艇在什么方位
Sonar, where is the enemy vessel?
方位角330° 距离船首右舷四千米
Bearing 330°, 4,000 meters off our starboard bow.
我方鱼雷还在运行
Our torpedo is running true.
即将命中敌方军舰 倒计时
Impact with enemy submarine in…
三 二 一
three… two… one.
怎么没显示命中
Where was the impact?
舰长 敌方舰艇消失了
Captain, enemy submarine has vanished.
突然不见了
It's gone, sir.
这是什么情况
I don't understand.
目标从没出现过
He was never there.
我们在追逐一个幻影
We've been chasing a phantom.
可他刚才明明就在那儿 仪器是不会撒谎的
It was right there. The instruments don't lie.
但今天是个例外
They lied to us today.
-武器官 关闭鱼雷发射程序 -是 舰长
-Weapons, shut down our torpedo. -Aye, Captain.
关闭鱼雷发射程序
Shutting down torpedo.
所有人解除作战状态
Secure from battle stations.
这也是我们出海测试的原因
This is why we have sea trials.
系统仍然存在缺陷
There's a bug in the system.
躲在机器里的幽灵
A ghost in the machine.
-该打道回府了 -舰长
-It's time to go home. -Captain!
我方鱼雷没有响应 正在朝我们袭来
Our own torpedo is not responding. It's coming right at us!
-我们被锁定了 打击距离400米 -见鬼
-Our torpedo's homing, range 400 meters! -Oh, my God.
改用缆控 关闭发射程序
Wire command. Shut down our weapon!
我方鱼雷还在逼近 还有200米
Our torpedo's still closing, range 200 meters!
释放所有主压载舱蓄水 拉响碰撞警报
Blow all main ballast tanks! Sound the collision alar--
阿姆斯特丹
外卖到了
Food delivery.
有人吗
Hello?
对接代号
Designator.
别紧张
Easy.
对接代号
Designator.
代号IZ254
India-Zulu-254.
BE11
Bravo-Echo-11.
不 还不行
No, not yet.
你还得问我安全验证问题
You need to ask me the security question first.
没错 抱歉
Oh, yeah. Sorry.
我们的誓言是什么
What is the oath?
无论生死皆隐于世
We live and die in the shadows
为我们珍爱之人
for those we hold close
也为不曾谋面之人
and for those we never meet.
放桌子上吧
You can put it on the table.
嘿
Hey.
欢迎加入碟中谍小组
Welcome to the IMF.
你的选择是正确的
You made the right choice.
是 长官
Sir.
晚上好 亨特先生
Good evening, Mr. Hunt.
很久没联系了
It's been a long time.
人生是我们每一次选择的结果
Our lives are the sum of our choices
我们终将无法逃避过去
and we cannot escape the past.
三十年前你面临过一次选择
Thirty years ago, you were offered the choice.
加入碟中谍小组 又或者锒铛入狱
Join the IMF or spend your life in prison.
因为你过人的天赋 政府原谅了你的过失
Because of your unique natural talents, your government forgave you.
但这不代表我们会忘记一切
But we will never forget.
正如你永远无法忘记多年之前
Just as you will never forget the death
是她的死把你带到了我们面前
that brought you to us all those years ago.
这是为了提醒你 遵守誓言并效忠于我们
This is to remind you of your oath and allegiance to us.
这次任务的风险比以往都要高
The stakes of this mission are higher than ever.
你一贯不服从指令的行为将不会被容忍
Your habitual rogue behavior will not be tolerated.
如果你选择接受任务 请仔细听清以下内容 它们十分重要
Should you choose to accept, it is imperative that you listen.
政府正在寻找一把钥匙
Your government is searching for a key.
其用途对于我们来说至关重要
Its purpose, its vital importance to us,
具体原因你不必关心
is none of your concern.
你需要关心的是 你的朋友伊尔莎浮士德也牵扯其中
What should concern you is the involvement of your friend Ilsa Faust.
(悬赏 五千万美元)
她在伊斯坦布尔杀了一名快递员
She killed a courier in Istanbul.
我们相信 那人手里握着半把 我们正在寻找的钥匙
And we believe he was carrying one half of the key we're searching for.
至于她为何会插手这件事 至今还是个谜
Why she has chosen to interfere in this affair is a mystery,
正如她的下落一样
as are her whereabouts.
但可以肯定的是 政府正在悬赏要她的性命
What is certain is that your government has put a price on her head
而那些赏金猎人 已经开始行动了
and these bounty hunters are out to collect it.
他们从未带回来过活口
They never bring a fugitive back alive.
甚至连具全尸都不会留
And rarely in one piece.
他们正在前往阿拉伯沙漠的鲁卜哈利地带
We believe they're headed for the Arabian Desert's Empty Quarter
寻找你的朋友
in search of your friend.
找到那些赏金猎人 也许就能找到你的朋友
Find the bounty hunters, and you may just find her.
若你选择接受 本次任务为
Your mission, should you choose to accept it,
夺取目标钥匙 并把它带给我们
is to acquire the key and deliver it to us.
完成任务后 伊尔莎的命运将由你决定
What happens to Ilsa after that is up to you.
还是老规矩 如果你或你团队的任何成员被捕或被杀
As always, if any members of your team are caught or killed,
部长将否认对你们的行动知情
the secretary will disavow any knowledge of your actions.
这条消息将会在五秒之后自动销毁
This message will self-destruct in five seconds.
祝你好运 伊森
Good luck, Ethan.
阿 拉 伯 沙 漠
也  门  边  境  附  近
走吧
Come.
伊森
Ethan.
摆在我们面前的到底是什么
So what are we dealing with?
这个所谓的"智体"它有着多重不同的身份
This "entity" has multiple personalities,
有时它就像电脑病毒一样 有时又如同绦虫或僵尸网络
at times behaving like a computer virus then a tapeworm, then a botnet.
情 报 部 门 通 气 会
华 盛 顿
它会肆意扭曲和修改 接触到的所有数字信息
Distorting any and all digital information with which it comes in contact.
一旦感染
Once infected,
所有以数字形式记录 存储和传输的信息 都将有可能被篡改
nothing recorded, stored or transmitted digitally can be trusted as fact.
最初 它的目标集中在新闻和社交媒体上
At the outset, it concentrated primarily on news and social media,
当时我们并没有在意 因为那通常和我们的利益一致
which was of little concern to us as it often suited our purposes.
直到六个月前
Until six months ago,
智体入侵了沙特阿拉伯的情报局
when the entity breached Saudi Arabia's General Intelligence Directorate.
还夺取了他们的机密技术 可自主学习的人工智能
And assimilated their top secret active learning AI
然后就在云端消失得无影无踪
before vanishing into the cloud.
随后感染率在一夜之间增长了上万倍
Subsequent attacks increased ten-thousandfold overnight,
正以指数倍疯狂传播
spreading exponentially.
也就是说 智体已经拥有了
Indicating that the Entity has since become
感知能力
sentient.
意思是它会自主思考了
You're telling me this thing has a mind of its own?
仅在过去的三周内
Over the last three weeks alone,
它就已经入侵了我们的卫星通讯系统 联邦储备银行
it has accessed our satellite telecommunications, the Federal Reserve,
股票市场 还有全国电网
the stock market and the national power grid.
航空局 美国宇航局 还有各个联合军种的分支机构
The FAA, NASA and the combined branches of our military.
而且不光是我们 它也感染了其他国家 以及欧洲中央银行系统
And we're not alone. It has penetrated the World and European Central Banks.
还侵入了多国的国防 金融 基础设施系统
Gained entry to the major defense, finance and infrastructure systems
包括俄罗斯 印度 以色列 澳大拉西亚和整个欧洲
of Russia, India, Israel, Australasia, all of Europe.
那它对这些系统具体做了些什么
And what did it do to all of these systems exactly?
什么都没做
Nothing.
什么都没吗
Nothing?
它来去自如
It came and it went,
在最明显的地方留下痕迹
leaving fingerprints where they could easily be found
就是为了向我们传达一条明确的信息
and sending a very clear message.
"我会卷土重来"
"I shall return."
无论它最终的目的是什么 我们都无力阻止它
Whatever its ultimate goal is, we're powerless to stop it.
目前它的全部力量 都集中指向了一个目标
The full force of its energy is now directed at a single objective.
整个世界的情报网络
The world's intelligence networks.
这是我们目前所知晓的真相
The very truth as we know it.
整个情报部门都在全力以赴用纸质文档
The entire intelligence community is racing to archive hard copies
保存已确认属实的数据库信息
of our fact-positive knowledge bases
以防我们最安全的数据库遭到入侵 或被破坏
before our most secure data centers are breached and corrupted.
但那也只是时间问题
Which is only a matter of time.
智体非常清楚
The Entity will know precisely
如何削弱我们的优势 并准确利用我们的弱势
how to undermine our every strength and exploit our every weakness.
如何将我们的盟友变成敌人
How to turn our allies into enemies
将我们的敌人 变成侵略者
and our enemies into aggressors.
为什么不隔离情报网络的服务器呢
Why not air-gap our intelligence servers?
完全切断它们与外界的联系
Cut them off from the outside world entirely?
我们已经这么做了
We already have.
可是 服务器仍然需要人工维护
But servers require humans to maintain them.
而人是所有安全链中最薄弱的环节
And humans are the weakest link in any security chain,
尤其在面对缺乏信仰 无依无靠 道德品质低的敌人时
especially when dealing with a godless, stateless, amoral enemy.
它一直在暗处耐心地倾听 读取 观察我们
One that has been patiently listening, reading, watching.
收集我们最私密的个人信息 年复一年
Harvesting our deepest personal secrets for years.
它可以欺骗 勒索 贿赂任何人 甚至成为它想成为的人
Able to beguile, blackmail, bribe or be anyone it wants.
还能利用我们对一个精心构筑的 数字世界的彻底依赖
And to manipulate us at will through our total dependence
随意操控我们每一个人
on a carefully constructed digital reality.
一个无处不在的敌人
An enemy that is everywhere
同时又无处可寻
and nowhere
虚无缥缈的敌人
and has no center.
好吧 所以你们的意思是
All right, so what you're telling me is,
作为全世界最出色的情报战术组织的你们
the most awesome goddamn intelligence and tactical apparatus on the planet
都没有办法除掉这个智体
has no way of killing this thing.
我们并不想除掉它 长官
You don't want to kill it, sir.
而是要控制它
You want to control it.
那要怎么实现呢 基特里奇先生
And how do we do that, Mr. Kittridge?
中情局在克里姆林宫的线人说
The CIA's assets in the Kremlin informed us
俄方将大部分情报活动都集中在了
that the Russians have focused the majority of their intelligence activity
寻找一把由两把钥匙组成的十字钥匙上
on acquiring two halves of a cruciform key.
-开什么锁的钥匙 -暂时还不确定
-And what does it unlock? -Not exactly sure.
但俄方似乎确信这把钥匙
But the Russians seem to believe that it somehow has
可以让那个神秘的智体停止运行
the power to deactivate our mysterious Entity.
所以 不难推测
Though, ideally,
他们希望能控制它 利用它
they hope to control it, harness it.
你真的相信吗 基特里奇
Do you believe that, Kittridge?
重点在于 全世界其他国家都信了
What matters is that the rest of the world believes it.
日本 印度 德国 英国都信了
Japan, India, Germany and the Brits believe it.
但却没有人
And yet no one,
就连我们最亲密的盟友
not even our closest allies,
都没有和我们提过只字片语
have willingly whispered one word of it to us.
这恰好证明 全世界都在想办法
Which would indicate that there's a global race on
得到这把钥匙
to acquire the two halves of this key.
参与其中的每一个国家 都不是为了要除掉它 长官
Every nation in it for themselves, not to kill this thing, sir,
而是想将它变成武器
but to weaponize it.
并借此力量建立一个全新的 不容抗衡的
And, in so doing, establish a new, incontestable form
全球统治地位
of global dominance.
怎样才能先找到钥匙
How do we find this key first?
我们得知有个买家 在接下来的72个小时内
Well, we know that a buyer is passing somewhere through the Middle East
会经过中东的某个地区
sometime in the next 72 hours.
我们相信他已经拿到了其中一半钥匙
We believe that he already has one half of this key.
"你们相信"
You believe.
当然 还不能确定钥匙的真假
At this point, we can't be certain it's not a counterfeit.
那么要怎么验证呢
How would you verify that?
想要验证其中一把钥匙的真伪 就只能靠
The only thing that can authenticate one genuine half of the key is
另一半钥匙 只有两把真的才能匹配
the other genuine half of the key--its true mate, if you will.
算是一种安全机制吧
We think it's some sort of fail-safe.
要怎么找到另一半呢
How do we find its mate?
我们相信另一半钥匙
Well, we believe the other genuine half of the key
在这个女人手里
was in the hands of this woman.
她是谁
Who is she?
伊尔莎浮士德
Ilsa Faust.
前英国情报局特工
Former British Intelligence.
-她现在在哪儿 -她已经死了 长官
-Where is she now? -She's dead, sir.
她是被… 抱歉
She was--excuse me--
被一群雇佣兵杀死的 所谓的赏金猎人
killed by mercenaries looking to collect a bounty.
谁悬的赏金
And who put up the bounty?
鉴于她的身份 谁都有可能
Given her body of work, could have been anyone.
所以任何人都可能拿到那一半钥匙
So anyone could have her half of the key?
也不是任何人
Not just anyone.
我派了一个人前去找她
I sent a man to find her.
这世上她唯一信得过且愿意托付钥匙的人
The only man she would have entrusted with her half of the key.
那他拿到钥匙了吗
Does he have it, Kittridge?
目前我还不知道 长官 他…拒绝露面
Well, at present, I don't know that, sir. He's refused to come in.
拒绝
Refused?
这家伙是什么人
Who the hell is this guy?
这是机密
That's classified.
我可是这个国家的情报局局长
I'm the goddamn Director of National Intelligence.
请问有什么是我不能知道的吗
What exactly is it I'm not supposed to know about?
IMF
The IMF.
-基特里奇先生 -世界银行
-Mr. Kittridge. -The world bank.
不 您说的是国际货币基金组织
No, that's the International Monetary Fund.
-基特里奇先生 -我说的是另一个IMF 我们的
-Mr. Kittridge. -No, I mean the other IMF. Ours.
全名到底是什么
What does it stand for?
碟中谍任务小组
Impossible Mission Force.
-开什么玩笑 -这恐怕不是玩笑
-You're not serious. -I'm afraid he is.
那他们到底是做什么的
And what do they do exactly?
就像他们的名字 不可能完成的任务
It's just as the name implies. Whatever the rest of us can't.
负责人是谁
And who is in charge?
他们并不会按部就班地听从指令 我们一般只会…
They're not ones to take orders in the traditional sense. We more or less…
给他们留言
leave word.
Leave word.
基特里奇先生
Mr. Kittridge, sir.
碟中谍小组不属于任何情报部门 他们直接向总统汇报
The IMF operates outside the community and answers directly to the president.
让我来捋一下
So let me get this straight.
每当你们遇到无法完成的任务时
When there's a mission none of you can handle,
你们就会选择给一个神秘人留言
you just leave word for a nameless man
然后祈祷他可以完成任务
and hope he gets the job done.
是这样吗
Is that it?
前提是他愿意接受任务
Should he choose to accept it.
他们凭什么有权选择接不接受任务
What the hell kind of outfit gets to choose what orders to accept?
建立该小组的初衷就是为了
The IMF was expressly created
确保不会出现意想不到的后果
to ensure there would be no unintended consequences.
如果他们无法保证任务的最终结果
If they cannot ensure a mission's ultimate outcome,
他们可以选择拒绝
they're authorized to decline.
我明白
I understand.
你很生气
You're upset.
我没生气 基特里奇
I'm not upset, Kittridge.
你说有话想对我说
You wanted me to listen.
所以我就来听听
This is me listening.
好吧
All right.
是我悬赏要伊尔莎的命
I put the bounty on Ilsa's head.
但我也跟你说了怎么找到她
I also told you how to find her!
我没让她去偷钥匙 她出于她自己的原因偷了那把钥匙
And I didn't ask her to steal the key. She did that for reasons of her own.
可是 一直以来不都是这样吗
But that's the pattern, isn't it?
你一次次帮她摆脱困境 她却总是一次次又陷进去
You get her out of trouble and she always found her way back in.
等等 伊尔莎
Wait! Ilsa.
伊尔莎 别激动 等等 是我
Ilsa, wait! It's me!
是我
It's me.
没事了
It's okay.
听我说 他们认为你死了 那就将错就错
Listen to me! You're dead! You stay dead!
伊森 等等
Ethan, wait!
我不会向你道歉的 亨特
I'm not going to apologize to you, Hunt.
利用你是我的职责所在
It's my job to use you.
就像你的职责就是完成任务
Just like it's your job to be of use.
所以你到底有没有完成你的任务
Did you accomplish your mission or not?
无论这把钥匙的另一半在哪里
Wherever the other half of this is,
无论它们能打开什么
whatever the completed key unlocks,
我都会弄个明白
I will find it.
弄明白之后呢
And then what?
智体不该交给任何人去掌控
No one should be trusted with control of the Entity.
我要毁了它
I mean to kill it.
伊森
Ethan,
下一次世界大战将不会是冷战
the next world war isn't gonna be a cold one.
它将是一场枪林弹雨 充满血腥的战争
It's gonna be a shooting war, a ballistic war
为了争夺日益减少的生态资源
over a rapidly shrinking ecosystem.
为了争夺那些仅存的能源
It's gonna be a war for the last of our dwindling energy,
为了最后一滴水 最后一口空气
drinkable water, breathable air.
掌握智体的人就等于掌握了真相
Whoever controls the Entity controls the truth.
而对于是非对错的定义
The concepts of right and wrong
在接下来的几百年里 都将由掌控智体的人说了算
can be clearly defined for everyone for centuries to come.
你听听自己在说什么
Do you even hear yourself?
你那些所谓的 为了正义而战的日子
Your days of fighting for the so-called greater good
已经结束了
are over.
你需要选择一个阵营
You need to pick a side.
我的阵营始终只有一个
I'm on the same side I've always been on.
不要妨碍我
Stay out of my way.
这我做不到
I can't do that.
我们会去找你 全世界都会追着你不放
We're gonna be coming after you. The world's gonna be coming after you.
无论如何 你内心坚持的那个使命
And one way or another, this mission of yours
都会让你付出沉重的代价
is gonna cost you dearly.
我要是不接电话 很快就会有人冲进来
If I don't get that, we're gonna have company real soon.
喂
Hello?
请邓林格局长接电话
Director Denlinger, please.
局长他现在不方便接电话 有什么事吗
Director is unavailable at the moment. How can I help you?
-请问您是哪位 -中情局局长尤金基特里奇
-To whom am I speaking? -CIA Director Eugene Kittridge.
-对接代号 -"低音音符" 统统小写 当中没有空格
-Designator? -"Bassnote," lowercase, all one word.
-长官 出了一点状况 -是吗
-Sir, we have a situation. -No kidding.
十分钟前 我们发现您的副手在他家中昏迷不醒
Your adjutant was found unconscious in his home ten minutes ago.
应该是被下了药
It appears he was drugged.
我知道了
I understand.
事态恐怕很严重
I don't think you do, sir.
警卫发现就在十五分钟之前 他刚进入了这栋大楼
Security has him entering this facility 15 minutes ago.
我知道了 谢谢
I understand, thank you.
您现在是不是不方便讲话
Are you able to speak freely?
-没错 谢谢 -我们马上派人过去
-No, thank you. -A security team is on their way.
如果您现在有危险 请在我数到五之前挂断电话
If you're in any danger, simply hang up the phone before I count to five.
一 二…
One, two--
现在你打算怎么离开这里
So just how do you plan on getting out of here?
当我没问
Of course.
碟 中 谍 7
致    命    清    算
第  一  章  ( 上 )
阿    联    酋
阿尔扎夫拉空军基地
听好了
Listen up.
现有一名美国特工对自己的国家表示不满
An American operative with a grievance against his country
现处于失踪以及失控状态
is missing and has malfunctioned.
他的行为可能会威胁到我们国家的利益
His agenda represents a threat to our national interests
必须不惜一切代价清除该隐患
and he must be neutralized at all cost.
他身上所携带的所有物品都十分重要
Anything in this man's possession is of vital importance
必须完好无损地截获
and must be captured intact.
不必顾及目标人物性命
The man himself is expendable.
但不要低估他的实力
He is not to be underestimated.
此人善于伪装 诡计多端 破坏力极强 且善用心理战术
A master of infiltration, deception, sabotage and psych warfare.
总而言之 女士们先生们
For all intents and purposes, ladies and gentlemen,
他就是个会读心 善于伪装的麻烦人物
a mind-reading, shape-shifting incarnation of chaos.
所以 出于对你们自身 以及队友的安全考虑
So, for your safety and the safety of those around you,
在确认他彻底断气之前
do not consider him secure
绝对不能对这个家伙掉以轻心
unless you have driven a wooden stake through his open heart.
这不是演习
This is not a drill.
一只具有意识 会自主学习
A self-aware, self-learning,
还会吞噬真相的数字寄生虫
truth-eating digital parasite
正滋生于整个网络之中
infesting all of cyberspace.
这反正是迟早的事
Well, it was bound to happen sooner or later.
而有了这两半钥匙
And the two halves of this key
就拥有了控制智体的工具
just might provide the means of controlling this Entity.
也就是说各国政府会为了这把钥匙 不惜杀了我们
Meaning every government on the planet would kill us just to get that key.
包括我们自己的国家
Including our own.
一点没错
Exactly.
他们是让我们执行一个还没开始
Putting us on an unsanctioned mission
就已经万劫不复的任务
which has gone rogue before it even started.
严格来说 我们现在的对话 就已经犯了叛国罪了
Meaning this very conversation is technically an act of treason.
而这对我们来说就像…家常便饭
Or as we like to call it, Monday.
现在该怎么做
So what's the play?
有个买家会坐746号航班 从阿姆斯特丹过来 在这儿停留半小时
A buyer's coming in on Flight 746 from Amsterdam for a 30-minute layover,
并利用这段时间买下这半把钥匙
at which time he is hoping to purchase that half of the key.
所以按理说来 那个买家
And it stands to reason the buyer will have
身上一定会带着另一半钥匙
the other half of the key somewhere on their person.
因为那是检验我们这把钥匙的唯一方法
Being the only way to authenticate our half.
那么 要怎样认出那个买家呢
So how do we identify the buyer?
这个辐射计数器
This Geiger counter
可以检测到蕴藏在买家那把钥匙里的
will detect a radiological signature of the dragon's egg
放射性特征
embedded in the buyer's key.
这副眼镜配有增强现实系统
The augmented-reality overlay in these glasses
能让我们找到目标
will lead us to it.
还挺厉害的
Oh, that's very clever.
所以 先找到那个买家 偷他的钥匙 轻松搞定
So, you ID the buyer, pick his pockets, Bob's your uncle.
-不 -我说呢
-No. -No. Of course not.
如果不知道用途 就算拿到两半钥匙也没用
The complete key is of no value if we don't know what it unlocks.
所以 你是真的打算把我们这一半卖给他
So you're going to sell the buyer our half of the key.
而我们负责弄清楚他坐哪班航班转机
While we figure out the buyer's connecting flight
最后让你也登上那架飞机
and book you a seat on that plane.
这样你就能一路跟着那把钥匙
So you can follow the key wherever it goes.
你希望钥匙的最后得主会知道它的用途
Which you hope is into the hands of someone who knows what it unlocks.
正是如此
Precisely.
所以拿到完整的钥匙
Finding the completed key
仅仅是个开始
is only the beginning.
这世界的命运 就看这钥匙究竟能打开什么了
The fate of the world depends on finding whatever it unlocks.
那家伙 你认识他
This guy, you know him?
我们没有私交
Not personally.
但有私人恩怨
But it is personal.
谢谢
Thank you.
-等等 那是什么 -什么
-Hey, what's that? -What?
"安全警报 可疑包裹正运往威尼斯"
Security alert. Suspicious bag on its way to Venice.
不见了 可能是警报器误报了
Nope, it's gone. Must have been a false alarm.
指挥部 这里是行动组 他在哪儿
Overwatch, Snap Shot. Where's he at?
这里是指挥部 发现目标
Snap Shot, Overwatch. I have him.
2号航站楼 15号登机口 往南去了
Terminal B, Gate 15, headed south.
-我可以的 -可以才怪
-I am so. -You are not.
伊森 不如你来告诉我们的老朋友"巡网猎手"
Ethan, would you care to explain to our friend, the Net Ranger,
其实我跟他写代码的能力不相上下
how I am just as capable of writing code as he is?
我不发表意见
No comment.
所以你觉得这位"幽灵黑客"
What, you figure Phineas Phreak here
可以单枪匹马找到除掉智体的办法
is gonna single-handedly work out a way to kill the Entity
而我只能打打下手
while I just hold his soldering iron?
-有这可能 -毋庸置疑
-Probably. -Definitely.
闪开 让开
Out of the way!
告诉我他的位置
Tell me where he is.
-他在哪儿 -蓝色西装 就在你前面
-Where is he? -Blue suit. Right in front of you.
-不是他 -是他没错
-It's not him. -It's him.
-我说了 不是他 -可我要告诉你
-I'm telling you, it's not him. -And I'm telling you,
面部识别匹配度高达…
facial comes back with a perfect--
你是怎么做到的
How did you do that?
没什么系统是"幽灵黑客"黑不进的
No one is safe from Phineas Phreak.
-找到他了 -在哪儿
-I got him! -Where is he?
5号航站楼 5号登机口
Terminal E, Gate 5.
该死 那可是机场的另一边
Goddamn it, that's clear on the other side of the airport.
伊森 他们去5号航站楼了 你可以在这边畅行无阻了
Ethan, they're headed to Terminal E. That side of the airport is all yours.
-多谢了 卢瑟 看到买家了 -看到了
-Thank you, Luther. I see the buyer. -Got him.
他叫奥拓冯博克 瑞士公民
The buyer is Otto Von Bork. Swiss national.
他要转机去威尼斯 30分钟后乘坐1031号航班
He's connecting to Venice, departing in 30 minutes on Flight 1031.
班吉 帮我弄张机票
Benji, get me on that flight to Venice.
没问题 飞往威尼斯的1031号航班 稍等
Yep, Flight 1031 to Venice. Stand by.
伊森 出什么事了
Ethan, what just happened?
-他被人撞了 -撞了 什么叫被人撞了
-He was bumped. -Bumped? What do you mean, bumped?
那个女的是个扒手 盯着她 告诉我她是谁
That woman picked his pocket. Tag her. Tell me who she is.
(1031号航班 飞往威尼斯)
卢瑟 关掉对讲
Luther, mute our comms.
-怎么了 -那个包是1031号航班的
-What is it? -That bag was on its way to Flight 1031.
什么包
What bag?
就是几分钟前那个警报 那个可疑的包
There was a suspicious bag alert a few minutes ago.
-这包怎么了 -它当时在运往1031的传送带上
-So what about it? -It was on its way to Flight 1031.
去威尼斯的 是那个买家的航班 也是伊森的航班
To Venice. It's the buyer's plane. It's Ethan's plane.
卢瑟 收到没 她什么来头
Luther, do you copy? Who is she?
如果刚才不是误报
What if it wasn't a false alarm?
如果是有人想在那飞机上放一个炸弹呢
What if somebody's trying to smuggle a bomb onto that plane?
也可能是智体故意想让我们这么想 为了阻止伊森上飞机
And what if that's what the Entity wants us to think to keep Ethan off that plane?
-卢瑟 出什么事了 -要跟他说吗
-Luther, what's happening? -Should we warn him?
-先别说 -伙计们 能听到我说话吗
-No. -Guys, guys? You hear me?
去找那个包 我告诉你在哪儿 快去
Find that bag. I'll direct you. Go.
卢瑟 告诉我是不是出事了
Luther, just tell me, is there something wrong?
不必担心 都在控制之中
Nothing to worry about. It's under control.
找到她了
Got her.
那女的的信息 传过去了
Info on the woman is coming… now.
(珠宝偷窃 欺诈 勒索 抢劫)
不管这女的是谁 她绝不是一个间谍
Whoever she is, she's no spy.
她是个小偷
She's a thief.
怎么走 卢瑟
Where am I going, Luther?
班吉 在你左边有一扇大门
Benji, there's a door on your immediate left.
我现在给你解锁
I'm unlocking it now.
(管控区域)
那个包在01833号传送带上
The bag you're after is on tray 01833
正在向西北角移动
heading towards the northwest corner of the facility.
收到
Copy that!
嗨
Hi.
你好啊
Hello.
我懂了
Oh, I get it.
你认错人了
You thought I was someone else.
我对这套没兴趣
I'm not interested.
给我个机会
Give me a chance.
我要叫了哦
I'll scream.
请随意
Please do.
你到底想干吗
What do you want?
这把钥匙
This key.
是你从那个人的口袋里偷来的
The one you picked from that man's pocket.
它一文不值
It's worthless
如果没有它的话
without this key.
但放在一起
But together
它们就价值U盘里的
they're worth four million in cryptocurrency
400万数字货币
that man was carrying on a flash drive.
我对此一无所知
Well, I wouldn't know anything about that.
那这U盘为什么会在你口袋里
Then why was this drive in your pocket?
你到底是谁
Who are you?
你有同伴吗
You working with someone?
从来没有 我向来喜欢单干
Never. I'm strictly single-0.
今天你有了
Today you got a partner.
我需要这U盘的原主人
I need the man you stole this from
完成一笔交易 并带着它们离开
to complete a transaction and leave this airport with both of these
而且不能让他知道自己被偷了
without ever knowing his pocket was picked
现在距离他登机还有…
and before he boards his flight in--
-7分钟 -7分钟
-Seven minutes. -Seven minutes.
偷东西你是个好手
We both know you're a good pickpocket.
看看你还东西的本事吧
Let's see what kind of put-pocket you are.
你是想让我把它放回去
You expect me to put it back.
我知道你会的
Oh, I know you will.
你是个小偷 你只想要钱
You're a thief. You want the money.
而钱我可以给你
And I can give it to you.
你自己选吧 干还是不干
Your choice. You're in or you're out.
好吧
All right.
要怎么做
So what's the play?
你最好知道自己在干什么
I sure hope you know what you're doing.
女士先请
After you.
对了 我不需要这个
Oh, I won't be needing this.
我不抽烟
I don't smoke.
留着吧 当是纪念我们的相识
Keep it. Something to remember me by.
伊森 她从那个买家那儿 偷来的那把钥匙匹配不上
Ethan, the alloy in that key she took off the buyer doesn't match.
-是把假的 -我早就猜到了
-It's counterfeit. -I expect nothing less.
但我们的目标不变 还是得让他带着两把钥匙离开
But that doesn't change our objective. The buyer has to leave with both keys.
说话啊 卢瑟 我该往哪儿走
Talk to me, Luther! Where am I going?
班吉 顺着前面的楼梯往下走
Benji, head down the stairs in front of you
包应该就在那里
and the bag should be right there.
好的 我到了
Okay. I'm there. I'm there.
是他了
That's him.
就在你前面
Right in front of you.
别激动 嘿 抱歉 我们认错人了
Okay, okay. Hey, sorry. Thought you were somebody else.
亨特在耍我们
Hunt's jerking our chain.
所有人都有 两人一组 分头找
Everybody! Two-man teams, spread out.
伊森 我们的美国朋友好像开窍了
Ethan, our American friends are getting wise.
他们开始分头搜索机场了
They're breaking up and canvassing the airport.
你要保持警惕了
Keep your eyes peeled.
该怎么称呼你
So, what do I call you?
叫我格蕾丝吧 你呢
How about Grace? And you?
听好了 格蕾丝
Well, listen, Grace.
这里不止我一个对钥匙感兴趣
You should know we're not the only interested party.
一会儿如果我让你跑 你就快跑
If I tell you to run, you run.
跑
Run?
越来越刺激了
This is getting exciting.
班吉 找到包了吗
Benji, have you got that bag?
找到了
I found it!
包里面装着一个圆柱形装置 我现在把它拿出来
There's a cylindrical device inside. I'm gonna take it out.
情况如何 卢瑟
How we doing, Luther?
伊森 买家就在你上方的候机区
Ethan, the buyer's in the waiting area above you.
扶梯最上面就是
Top of the escalator.
所有特工都在朝你这边过来
All units are headed in your direction.
他们随时可能会朝你这边扑过来
Your location is going to be crawling with agents anytime now.
不管它是什么 我好像把它激活了
Whatever it is, I've just activated it.
上面显示只有五分钟时间
Looks like we have five minutes.
-看上去像是个核弹 -有多大
-Also, it appears to be nuclear. -How big?
大到足够摧毁整个飞机场了
Big enough to matter to everybody in this airport, I suspect.
-你能拆掉它吗 -可我没有工具啊
-Can you disarm it? -I haven't got any tools!
-那就去找啊 -你让我上哪儿去…
-Then find some. -Where am I gonna find--
现在就要跑吗
Is this where we run?
暂时不用
Not yet.
班吉 炸弹拆得怎么样了
Benji, how are you doing with that bomb?
快点
Come on, come on.
打开了
I got it!
这是个柱形密码锁 一共有八个转盘
It's a cylinder cypher. There's eight wheels.
看样子每个转盘上有14个字母
Looks like 14 letters on each wheel.
那样的话 整整有15亿种组合
1.5 billion possible combinations.
差不多吧
Give or take.
我的天
Oh, my God.
又怎么了
What now?
转盘上的字母拼出了一条信息
The wheels--They spell out a message.
U.R.DUNN
U.R.DUNN.
不可能 我们绝不会的
No way. Not yet, we aren't.
不 卢瑟 不是D-O-N-E
No, Luther, not D-O-N-E.
是D-U-N-N
D-U-N-N.
那是我的姓氏
It's my last name.
它知道我是谁
It knows who I am.
等下 显示屏上有条消息
Hold on. There's a message on the display.
"我无口却能言 无翼却能飞 我是什么 "
"I speak without a mouth, I fly through the air without wings. What am I?"
你问的什么问题
You got me. What?
这是个谜语 我估计这东西是声控的
It's a riddle. I suspect this thing is voice-activated.
它想让我把答案说出来
It wants me to say the answer.
"我无翼却能飞"
"I fly through the air…"
是回声
An echo!
答对了
That's it! That's it!
好了 新问题
Okay, new message.
"你怕不怕死 "
"Are you afraid of death?"
-这算哪门子谜语 -这不是谜语
-What kind of a riddle is that? -It's not a riddle.
这是心理计量测试
It's a psychometric test.
你回答得越多 它就越了解你
The more questions you answer, the more it'll know about you.
"你怕不怕死" 不怕
"Are you afraid of death?" No!
-有用吗 -我撒谎了 被识破了
-Did it work? -I lied. It knows.
跟它说实话吧 快点
Just tell it the truth. Say it.
"你怕不怕死" 废话 有谁不怕
"Are you afraid of death?" Yes! Who isn't?
"什么东西一直在接近 却从未到达 "
Okay. "What's always approaching but never arrives?"
等等 这题我好像听过
Wait, I know this one.
倒计时还在继续 卢瑟
The clock is ticking, Luther.
猜谜不是我的强项 你催我也没用
Riddles aren't my thing, Benji. What more can I say?
快没时间了
We're running out of time!
他在那儿
There he is.
也太容易了吧
Oh, this is too easy.
抱歉打扰一下 伊森
Sorry to bother you, Ethan.
你知道什么东西一直在接近
Would you happen to know what's always approaching
却从未到达吗
but never arrives?
"什么东西一直在接近 却从未到达"
What is always approaching but never arrives?
明天
Tomorrow.
什么
What?
一直在接近却从未到达 是明天
Always approaching but never arrives. Tomorrow.
-是明天 -明天
-It's tomorrow. -Tomorrow.
对 没错 是明天
Tomorrow! Tomorrow!
对了 好了 下一个问题
Yes! Okay, next question.
把东西给我
Give me the goods.
-我会盯着你的 -怎么 不相信我吗
-I'll be watching. -You don't trust me?
卢瑟 出什么事了
Luther, what is happening?
没什么可担心的 所有事都在掌控之中
Nothing to worry about. Everything is under control.
好了 下一个问题
Okay, next question.
"谁或者什么对你来说最为重要 "
"Who or what is the most important thing to you?"
告诉它
Say it.
-可如果我… -我们别无选择 告诉它
-But if I---There's no other choice. Say it.
我的朋友们
My friends.
真是可恶
Bastard.
-他这是… -没错 他死了
-Is he---Yes, he is.
把钱和钥匙都给我
Give me the money, give me the key.
好了 下一题 "什么东西 你带走越多它就越大 "
Okay. "What gets bigger the more you take away?"
-是坑 -是坑 聪明 没错
-A hole. -A hole. Brilliant!
没有问题了 可还剩一个转盘
I've got no more questions and there's one more wheel.
连问题都没有 我要怎么给出答案
How am I supposed to give answers if I've got no questions?
那一定就是最后的考验
That must be your final test.
只剩45秒了
I've got 45 seconds!
现在怎么办
What happens now?
我正在想 别乱动
I'm thinking. Don't move.
卢瑟 我被包围了 需要一条出路 该往哪里走
I'm pinned down. Need a way out of here. Where am I going?
有个更严峻的问题 伊森
We have a bigger problem, Ethan.
可能今天没人能离开这里了
It's very possible no one is getting out of here.
什么
What?
行李传送处有个炸弹 是小型核弹
There's a bomb in baggage handling. A nuclear bomb.
刚才问你的那个问题是拆弹所需的密码
The question I asked you is part of the code for disarming it.
等一下 你先等一下
Stop, stop, stop!
为什么不早告诉我
Why didn't you tell me this?
你要处理的事够多了 我们不想打扰你
You had a lot going on. We didn't want to bother you.
听我说 发现核弹这种事 你们应该第一时间告诉我
Listen to me. A nuclear bomb is something you bother me with immediately.
-还有多少时间 -还剩二十秒
-How much time? -Twenty seconds.
二十秒
Twenty seconds?
等一下 还有一个谜语 我还在想 最后十五秒
There's one more riddle. I'm working on it. Fifteen seconds!
别急 什么谜语
Easy, easy. What's the riddle?
没等我给你解释完 我们就被炸飞了
In the time it takes me to explain, we'll all be dead!
别这样 班吉
Come on, Benji.
为什么我们总会弄成这样
Why do we always end up in these situations?
还剩十秒
Ten seconds.
九 八
Nine… eight…
七 六 五
seven… six… five…
(祝你好运)
我的天
Oh, my God.
怎么了
What is it?
-是空的 -什么叫是空的
-It's empty. -What do you mean, empty?
里面什么都没有
There's nothing inside.
她偷走了钥匙
She took the key.
-哪把 -我们那把 真的那把
-Which key? -Our key. The real key.
-什么 -卢瑟 快找到她
-What? -Luther, find her.
找到了 她往5号航站楼去了
I got her. She's headed for Terminal E.
-这不可能 -怎么了
-No, it can't be. -What is it?
卢瑟 班吉 中止行动 快走
Luther, Benji. Abort. Get out!
-要去哪里会合 -不会合了
-Where do we rendezvous? -We don't!
这次任务彻底终止 赶紧离开这里
This mission is terminated. Get out now.
亨特 嘿 给我站住 嘿
Hunt! Stop right there!
看到他没 去哪儿了
You see him? Where is he?
请让让
Excuse me! Excuse me!
抱歉
Sorry! Sorry! Sorry!
(罗马)
-快让开 -别挡道
-Move! -Move, move!
他一定就在附近
He's got to be here somewhere.
真是该死
Goddamn.
这里采用的是短波无线
What we have here is shortwave radio,
电磁音频记录 以及阴极射线管显示器
magnetic audio recording, cathode ray tube monitors.
不再依靠计算机运行
No more ones and zeros.
完全靠模拟信号来运行的线下安全屋
It's a fully analog, offline safe room,
可以抵御靠数字化运行的智体
shielded from our digitally-based Entity.
那信号要怎么传输进来
Where is this feed coming from?
靠冷战时期的科罗娜间谍卫星
CORONA spy satellite from the Cold War.
我都不知道我们还在用那些老古董
Had no idea we were still using those things.
确实很久没用了
Yeah, well, we weren't.
二十年前我们把它给了国家气象局
Gave them to the National Weather Service 20 years ago.
这是最后一个还能用的
This is the last one still functioning.
那这东西能帮我们找到你那位 神秘的碟中谍特工吗
So, will this thing help us find your nameless IMF man?
这点恐怕无能为力 长官
Nothing can do that, sir.
不过它可以帮我们监视这个女人
But it has allowed us to keep tabs on this woman.
我们发现他们俩在阿布扎比机场有过接触
She was seen with our man at the airport in Abu Dhabi.
她又是谁
Who is she?
她现在在哪儿
Where is she now?
你之所以在这儿 是因为意大利警方收到了匿名线报
You are here because Italian police received an anonymous tip
和你外貌相似的一个女人
that a woman matching your description
将会于今日下午从阿布扎比抵达这里
would be arriving on the afternoon flight from Abu Dhabi.
这个女人 手里持有很多国家的护照
This woman had multiple passports in her possession.
这本的主人 在圣彼得堡因诈骗而被通缉
This one is wanted for fraud in Saint Petersburg.
在安特卫普偷盗珠宝 在摩纳哥偷取艺术品
Jewel theft in Antwerp. Art theft in Monaco.
在米兰贪污 在孟买敲诈
Graft in Milan. Extortion in Mumbai.
而这本是我最喜欢的
But this is my favorite--
在里约热内卢拒捕
resisting arrest in Rio.
这不禁让我好奇
Which leads me to wonder,
里面哪个才是真正的你
which one of these women is you?
我从没见过这些护照
I've never seen these before in my life.
都是在你包里找到的
They were in your purse.
护照上也都是你的照片
And your picture is in every one.
-我能看看吗 -请便
-May I see? -Please.
照片里的人确实很像我
Yes, it's an amazing likeness,
可是 这不是我
but it isn't me.
我说了很多次了
As I keep telling you,
我是来自布莱顿的老师 我正在休假
I'm a schoolteacher from Brighton. I'm on a sabbatical.
不管你牵扯了什么事
Whatever you're involved in,
有一点很明显 你的敌人非常强大
you've obviously made some very powerful enemies.
好的
Okay.
她的律师到了
Her lawyer is here.
我的律师
My lawyer?
史佩茨法官
Magistrate Spezzi.
不好意思 您是…
I'm sorry. Who are you?
国际刑警
Interpol.
关于你们逮捕的那个 从阿布扎比来的女人
I've come regarding the arrest of the woman from Abu Dhabi.
我需要检查一下她被捕时身上的物品
I'll need to inventory the items on her person at the time of her arrest.
能看一下您的证件吗
May I see some identification, please?
其他东西呢
Where's the rest?
她的东西都在这儿了
I assure you, this is everything.
-请问怎么称呼 -她从阿布扎比离开时带了把钥匙
-What was your name? -She left Abu Dhabi with a certain key.
我们没看到钥匙
There was no key.
那钥匙形状独特
It was an unusual sort.
你可能会误把它当作挂坠
One that you could mistake for a pendant.
然后 把它挂在项链上
The kind that you'd be tempted to hang on a chain
送给你的阿米莉亚
around Amelia's neck.
阿米莉亚
Amelia?
你的妻子
Your wife.
你亲爱的女儿萨琳娜的母亲
Mother of your lovely daughter, Serena.
你不是国际刑警
You're not Interpol.
只要我愿意 我可以是
I am if I wish to be.
我能成为任何人 而且我无所不知
I can be anything, and I know everything.
就像我知道这不是你第一次中饱私囊了
I know this wouldn't be the first time you've helped yourself to stolen goods.
卡地亚手镯那次
A Cartier bracelet.
虽然你摆脱了嫌疑
You were cleared of suspicion,
但你把它送给了你的情妇瓦莱丽
but we both know you gave it to your mistress, Valeria.
就在8月21日 她29岁生日那天
On August 21st. Her 29th birthday.
你到底是谁
Who are you?
为了保险起见
I'm gonna have to search you,
我要搜一下身
just to be sure.
你的秘书她已经不在了
Your secretary's no longer with us.
谢谢 两位警官
Thank you officers.
坐吧
Please.
麻烦请到外面等一下 谢谢
You can wait outside. Thank you.
你 是你害我的
You. You did this.
是我报的警 但我没跟他们说你精彩的过去
I called the police. I didn't tell them about your colorful past.
要怪怪你自己
That's on you.
在被捕前 你把钥匙放到了 另一个乘客的口袋里
You put-pocketed that key on another passenger before you were arrested.
你们留了联系方式 相约稍后见面
You exchanged details and arranged to meet later on.
现在 有个毫不知情的人
Right now someone out there
在外面帮你保管着那把钥匙
hasn't the slightest clue they're holding on to that key for you.
一个不知情的快递员 作为同伙再合适不过了
An unwitting courier. The perfect accomplice.
我猜他是个男的 中年男人
I'm guessing a man… middle-aged?
那种一辈子都想 被你这样的美女注意到的男人
A man waiting his whole life to be noticed by a woman like you.
你是个孤儿
An orphan.
从小就很聪明 天生足智多谋
Highly intelligent. Inherently resourceful.
小时候条件不好 所以想要更好的物质生活
Growing up in poverty left you longing for the finer things.
甚至不惜去偷别人的
Other people's things.
有人看到了你的潜质 培养你 发挥你的天赋
Someone saw your potential and helped you hone your skills.
而这手艺也给了你想要的生活
Skills that gave you the life you thought you wanted.
定制的衣服 昂贵的美食 奢华的酒店
Tailored clothes, fine dining, luxury hotels.
你凭着这门手艺一直逍遥法外
Skills that kept you one step ahead of the law,
直到今天
until now.
我一个小女孩儿只不过是混口饭而已
You can't blame a girl for trying to make a dishonest living.
你根本不知道自己偷的是什么 不然你肯定不会这么干
You had no idea what you were stealing. Otherwise you never would have stolen it.
这样吧
Tell you what.
你把我弄出去 我就带你去找钥匙
You get me out of here, and I'll take you straight to the key.
我有更好的主意
I have a better idea.
你老老实实交代一切
You're gonna tell me everything.
我就考虑帮你逃出去
Then I'll think about getting you out of here.
先说说你的雇主是谁
Now start with who hired you.
别想撒谎 我能看得出来
And don't lie to me, because I'll know.
我也不知道雇主是谁
I have no idea who hired me.
我们基本上都是通过线上联络的
Contact with the client was almost entirely electronic.
-电子邮件 -短信
-Email? -Texts.
-加密的 -那当然
-Encrypted? -Naturally.
-"基本上" -什么
-Almost? -Pardon?
你刚才说你们"基本上"是通过线上联系的
You said contact with the client was "almost" entirely electronic.
在卢森堡的一个咖啡馆里有个秘密传递点
There was a dead drop in a café in Luxembourg.
-里面有个信封 -信封里装了什么
-An envelope. -What was in the envelope?
去阿布扎比的机票
A ticket to Abu Dhabi.
还有一张…
And…
你的照片
a picture of you.
给我的指令是在机场跟着你
My instructions were to follow you at the airport.
说届时你会跟着一个目标
You'd be tailing a mark.
而目标手里有把钥匙 还有四百万的数字货币
Said mark would have a key and four million in cryptocurrency.
对了 那个U盘没用 是空的
That drive was useless, by the way. It was empty.
我只有把你那半钥匙送到客户手里 才能拿到钱
The only hope I have of getting paid is to deliver your half of the key.
那个客户想让你把钥匙送到…
And you were instructed to deliver it to…
威尼斯
Venice.
去公爵府举行的派对 明晚午夜
Party at Ducale Palace. Tomorrow. Midnight.
你是在等谁吗
You expecting someone?
你在机场的"朋友" 几分钟前我在走廊看到他们了
Your friends from the airport. Saw them in the hallway a few minutes ago.
你怎么不早点告诉我
You could have said something sooner.
他们追的是你 又不是我
Well, they were chasing you, not me.
你个臭流氓
A pervertito!
不 别这样 格蕾丝
No, Grace.
不
No, no, no.
她是我的客户
She's my client.
不 格蕾丝
Grace.
不
No, no.
不 让开
No, no! Move! Move!
抱歉
Sorry!
怎么停车的
Who parks like that?
格蕾丝 快停车
Grace! You gotta pull over.
格蕾丝
Grace.
停下 听我说 我这是在帮你 格蕾丝
Pull over. Listen. I'm trying to help you! Grace!
把那女的带过来
Bring her to me.
你还好吗 没事吧 别
Are you okay? You okay? No, no, no.
你们走吧
We're okay.
把手给我
Give me your hand.
慢点 没事了
Slow, slow, slow. It's okay.
慢一点
Slow.
有没有受伤 没事吧 还好吗
Is anything broken? Are you okay? You okay?
亨特
Hunt!
都结束了
It's over!
放开那女孩儿
Let the girl go.
自己戴上手铐
Put the bracelets on.
动作快 快戴上 快点
There you go. Put them on. Do it!
别怕 他不会朝你开枪的
It's okay. He's not gonna shoot you.
放下武器
Put your weapons down now.
我们在执行特别行动 他是恐怖分子
Special Operations. He's wanted for terrorism.
该死 德加 快疏散妇女
Goddamn it, Degas, get rid of those women.
亨特 听我说
Hunt, listen to me. Listen to me.
放了她 戴上手铐
Let her go and put them on.
赶紧放下武器
Put your weapons down now.
一切都在掌控中
It's all under control.
不要冲动
It's okay! It's okay! It's okay!
大家快趴下 快 趴下
Everybody down! Get down!
-趴下 -找掩护
-Down, down! -Cover, cover! Cover!
-你来开车 -什么
-You're driving. -What?
不行 好吧
No, no, no!
动作快 快踩油门
Go, go, go. Hit the accelerator.
快点
Go, go, go!
快开
快上车
Get in!
很好 继续开
You're good. Just keep it going.
别停下
Don't stop.
看着车
Car, car, car.
别紧张 先踩刹车 然后重新启动
It's okay. Just put your foot on the brake. Start the car.
等等
Wait, wait, wait!
-嘿 怎么了 -我不干了 这种车我开不了
-What's happening? -I'm done. I'm not doing this.
有很多人在追我们
People are chasing us.
是的 我看到了 所以你来开车 快点
Yes, they are. You're driving. Now, come on.
那家伙到底是谁
Who is that person?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
-你还好吗 -一切结束才可能会好
-You okay? -I will be when this is over.
该死
Oh, man.
没事 见鬼
It's okay. It's okay.
感觉是个人都在追我们
Is there anyone not chasing us?
我们得换辆车
We gotta get rid of this car.
该死的摩托 真麻烦
Scooters! Damn it.
这是在干吗
What are we doing?
(安全车)
给咱们找辆新车
Finding us a new car.
好的
Okay.
-让我研究一下 -好的
-Just give me a second. -Yeah.
-谢谢 可以了 -好的
-Thanks. Okay? -Yeah.
-准备好了 -随时出发
-You ready? -I'm ready.
-你没事吧 -没事
-Wow. -You okay?
那个什么 我很抱歉 这车真是…
Yeah, look, I'm sorry. This is…
-没关系 -不 这车真是…
-It's okay. -No, this car, the way they…
没关系
It's okay.
这辆车的设计真的是…
No, the way they set them up, sometimes it's just…
-快走吧 -得适应一下
-Let's go. -It takes me…
交通摄像头通过面部识别 拍到了这位女性
Traffic cameras have picked up the woman on facial recognition.
她现在在一辆黄色菲亚特500上
She is now in a yellow Fiat 500.
各单位正在追捕中
Units are in pursuit.
这下你跑不了了
Now I got you.
看来甩掉他们了
Looks like we lost them.
好吧 我们现在…
Let's just--
闪开
Move, move, move!
婴儿车
Baby, baby, baby!
什么情况
Wait, what?
不 我不行
No, no, no.
快走
Go, go, go!
笔直开 往前走
Go straight.
-脚放开油门就好 -车子着火了
-Just take your foot off the accelerator. -We're on fire. We're on fire!
没着火 是轮胎 试着让车笔直开
It's the tires. Just try to go straight.
-冷静点 -它为什么在打转
-Hang on. -Why is it spinning?
很好
Good, good, good!
我搞定了 行了
I've got it, I've got it, I've got it.
-右转 往那儿开 那条路 -加油啊
-Turn right. Down there. Right there! -Come on!
往右边走 往右边
Got to go right. Turn right!
-到底是谁在开车 -你在开
-Who's driving? -You're driving.
快开 笔直开
Go, go, go. Just go straight.
快点
Go, go, go.
继续保持直行 保持直行
Just keep going straight.
左转了 左转也行 快开 快开 你开得很好
Or left. Go, go, go. You're doing good.
警察 好多警察
Cops! A lot of cops!
你来开
Take the wheel.
刹车
Brake, brake, brake.
好了 换你开
Okay, your wheel.
笔直开
Straight?
-右转 -明白
-Right, right, right. -Got it.
-再往哪儿开 -左转
-Which way now? -Left, left, left.
很好 继续开
Okay. You're good, you're good.
你得避开人
That's a person.
-看车 -看到了
-Car, car. -I see it!
踩油门
Hit it.
坐稳了
Hang on!
-现在什么情况 这是在往哪里开 -我也不知道
-What is happening? Where are we going? -I don't know.
好了 刹车
Okay, brake, brake, brake!
你别怪我
Don't hate me.
格蕾丝 格蕾丝
Grace? Grace!
快点
Come on, come on.
伊森
Ethan!
伙计 还等什么
Well, come on.
好吧 我们知道格蕾丝手里有一半钥匙
All right. We know Grace has one half of the key.
我们还知道今天午夜她会去公爵府
We also know she's gonna be at the Ducale at midnight.
那我们基本上算是知道 她要见的是谁了
And now we have a pretty good idea as to who will be waiting for her there.
在那儿举办活动的是我们最中意的
The event is being hosted by none other than
国际黑市军火贸易商 阿兰娜米特索普利斯
our favorite international arms trafficker and black marketeer, Alana Mitsopolis.
人称"白寡妇"
The White Widow.
她知道你的真实身份吗 还是说她依然以为
Does she know who you actually are or does she still think
你是那个臭名昭著的杀人犯 约翰拉克
you're the globally notorious mass murderer John Lark?
谁说我不是了呢
Who says I'm not?
她之前不是在巴黎悬赏要你的脑袋吗
Didn't she put a price on your head in Paris?
确实 但据说她和伊森私下了结了
She did indeed. She and Ethan, they worked it out.
你从没提过怎么了结的
You never did tell me how.
继续说正事 好吗
Can we continue, please?
好吧
Right.
所以说 就算今晚我们拿到了完整的钥匙
Assuming we get the complete key at the party tonight,
我们还是不知道它的用途 所以得找个知情的人
we still don't know what it unlocks, so we need to find somebody who does.
问题是 去哪儿找呢
The question is where to start looking.
那个炸弹总不会自己长脚走进机场
We figured that the bomb didn't just walk into the airport by itself.
对吧 肯定是有人带进去的
Right? Somebody put it there.
有人在为智体做事
Somebody working for the Entity.
这是我从机场监控那儿找到的所有视频
This is everything I captured from the security cameras at the airport
内容都在这儿 直到事情失控的那一刻
up to the minute everything went haywire.
而这是通过你的墨镜拍摄到的视频
And this is the feed from your AR sunglasses.
我一直在给当时所有在场的人 做面部识别对比
I've been running facial recognition on everyone in the airport.
看看有什么发现吗
See anything strange?
就像幽灵一样
It's like a ghost.
幽灵可没有倒影
Ghosts don't have reflections.
整个机场唯一没有身份的家伙
The only person in the airport with no identity.
也是唯一一个在机场 没有留下任何踪迹的家伙
The only man who can't be found anyplace else in the airport
除了这个倒影
except that reflection.
他的痕迹被清除了
He's being erased.
还是实时操作的
In real time.
是智体
The Entity.
智体在保护他
It's protecting him.
你看到他了 对吧
You saw him, didn't you?
我当时不确定
I wasn't sure.
那家伙是谁
Well, who is he?
一个我以为
Someone I thought
已经死了很久的人
died a long time ago.
很久以前的事了
In another life.
在我加入碟中谍之前
Before the IMF.
在我做出那个选择之前
Before I was offered the choice.
甚至可以说
And in a very real sense,
是他造就了今天的我
he made me who I am today.
他叫什么名字
Does he have a name?
他自称盖布瑞尔
He calls himself Gabriel.
你认识他
You know him.
没有人真正认识他
There is no knowing him.
他的过去没有任何记录
He has no recorded past.
智体帮他实现了这一点
The Entity made sure of that.
他是邪恶的化身
He's a dark messiah.
是智体钦点的信使
The Entity's chosen messenger.
在他的眼中 死亡
And he sees death
是他想要和世界分享的礼物
as a gift he wants to share with the rest of the world.
你怎么知道这些的
How do you know this?
我在军情六处还有些朋友
I still have a few friends left in MI6.
他们也同样担心 智体会落入英国政府的手里
Friends who are afraid of the British government gaining control of the Entity.
任何想要阻止这件事的行为 都会被视为叛国
Any attempt to try to stop them would be seen as an act of treason.
而你已经脱离了组织
And because you're disavowed,
所以你的朋友就向你寻求帮助
your friends called and asked you for help.
他们知道盖布瑞尔在为智体做事
They knew Gabriel serves the Entity.
他们还知道他会去伊斯坦布尔
They knew he was on his way to Istanbul
寻找一把十字钥匙的其中一半
to acquire one half of a cruciform key.
所以 我抢先了他一步
So I beat him to it.
随后基特里奇悬赏要你的命
And when Kittridge put a bounty on your head,
你就去了沙漠想躲起来
you went to the desert to hide.
谁知道那些赏金猎手还是找到了你
But somehow the bounty hunters found you anyway.
没错
Yes.
那么 你那些朋友有说过 那把钥匙是用来开什么的吗
So, did these friends of yours happen to say what the key unlocks?
军情六处认为 钥匙或许可以打开智体的源代码
MI6 suspects it leads somehow to the Entity's source code.
源代码
Source code.
你打算什么时候告诉我
When were you gonna tell me this?
现在不告诉你了吗
I'm telling you now.
你在军情六处的朋友 他们是怎么联系你的
Your friends at MI6, how'd they contact you?
你和他们通话了 还是见面了
Did you speak with them? Face to face?
我脱离了组织
I'm disavowed.
他们不能冒险来见我 所以 所有的联络…
They couldn't risk meeting me in person, so all communication--
都是通过电子 还有数字
Was electronic. Was digital.
我们不能确定那就是智体
No. We can't be sure that was the Entity.
也不能确定它不是
We can't be sure it wasn't.
除了现在的对话 我们无法确信外面的任何信息
We can't be sure anything is real outside of this very conversation.
你们不该来这儿
None of you should be here.
-伊森 -不 你不了解盖布瑞尔 但我了解
-Ethan---No. You don't know Gabriel. I do.
他享受的不是杀戮本身
It's not the killing he enjoys.
而是杀戮带给别人的痛苦
It's the suffering it causes.
他很清楚该如何对付我
And he knows the best way to get to me
就是通过你们
is through all of you.
如果盖布瑞尔知道我的事
And if Gabriel knows me…
智体也会知道
The Entity knows.
他想让我来这儿一定有他的原因
There's a reason he wants me here. There's…
就像他想让你们也来这儿一样 这是智体的意思
There's a reason he wants you here. It wants you here.
"谁或者什么 对你来说最为重要"
"Who or what is the most important thing to you?"
你们赶紧走 你们全都快走
No. You have to go. You all have to go.
-伊森 如果这正是它的目的呢 -就像它让我们离开机场那样
-Ethan, what if it wants us to leave? -Like you made us leave the airport.
如果它就是想让你一人去那个派对呢
What if it wants you alone at that party tonight?
那就如它所愿 至少我不用担心你们的安危
Then I go alone. At least I don't have all of you to worry about.
这就是我为什么一开始不告诉你的原因
This is exactly why I didn't want to tell you.
伊森 你正在和一个电脑算法 下四维国际象棋
Ethan, you're playing four-dimensional chess with an algorithm.
智体非常了解我们
The Entity knows who we are.
我们的行动它可能都考虑到了
Any move we make, it's probably considered it.
我们的一举一动 可能都在它的预判之中
Anything we do, we have to assume that it's counting on us to do it.
如果你想打败智体 就必须像它一样思考
If you want to beat this thing, you have to start thinking like it.
冷酷 无情 逻辑至上
Cold, logical, unemotional.
如果那把钥匙真的可以控制智体的话
If that key really does grant control of the Entity,
那无论如何都不能让盖布瑞尔得到它
Gabriel is the last person on Earth who should have it.
她说得对 伊森
She's right, Ethan.
不能让盖布瑞尔拿到钥匙
Gabriel cannot have that key.
和这次的任务相比 我们的性命不值一提
And none of our lives can matter more than this mission.
我决不接受
I don't accept that.
这是我第一次来威尼斯
It's my first time in Venice.
我也是第一次
It's mine, too.
请你喝一杯怎么样
Buy you a drink?
我在等人
I'm waiting for someone.
我也是
So am I.
我们可以一起等 我叫盖布瑞尔
We can wait together. I'm Gabriel.
随便吧
If you say so.
你是格蕾丝吧
And you're Grace.
东西不在我身上
I don't have it on me.
我也没指望你带着
I wouldn't expect you to.
更何况 我也不是为了钥匙而来
In any case, I'm not here for the key.
那你想怎么样
What do you want?
既然我们都在等人 我给你讲个小故事吧
Suppose while we're waiting I tell you a little story.
很明显你不是我要见的那个人
You're obviously not the person I came here to meet.
关于你的故事 格蕾丝
It's your story, Grace.
我知道它的结局
I know how it ends.
让我请你喝一杯 或许还可以改变呢
Let me buy you a drink and perhaps we can change it.
派对在等我们
Let's go to a party.
抱歉 先生
Excuse me, sir.
麻烦您跟我来
Would you please follow me?
有一点很重要 你得知道自己并没那么特别
It's important you understand that you're not unique.
三十年前
Thirty years ago…
一个叫玛丽的姑娘
her name was Marie.
她是第一个对我们那位朋友 深信不疑的女人
The first of many women who trusted our mutual friend.
那些女人身上都有他想要的东西
Women who all have something he wants.
她们各有各的困境 至少他会这么说
Women who are all in over their heads, or so he tells them.
听着耳熟吗
Sound familiar?
那个玛丽后来怎么了
What happened to Marie?
被他利用过的女人都只有一个下场
Same thing that happens to all the women he uses,
就像碰过那把钥匙的人一样
as well as anyone else who touches that key.
他根本不在乎那些人的死活
He doesn't care whether people live or die.
他在乎的只有他自己的目标
He cares only about his objective.
而现在 唯一挡在他面前的人
And right now, the only thing standing in his way
就是你
is you.
-我有什么理由相信你 -确实没有
-Why should I believe you? -You shouldn't.
你踏入了一个充满谎言的世界
You've stepped into a world of lies, Grace.
没有一个人会讲真话
Nothing anyone says is true.
当他说会保护你时 记住我刚才说的话
Just remember that when he promises to protect you.
格蕾丝
Grace.
好久不见了 伊森
It's been a long time, Ethan.
当年你应该杀了我的
You should've killed me when you had the chance.
晚上好 各位
Good evening, everyone.
这不是约翰拉克吗
If it isn't John Lark.
可惜这个身份是假的
Except it isn't, actually.
不过在你告诉我真名之前
But until you're ready to tell me your real name,
我只好继续叫你拉克了
Lark will have to do.
很高兴见到你 阿兰娜
It's good to see you, Alana.
你是盖布瑞尔吧 我没猜错吧
And you're Gabriel, I presume.
我对你可真是一无所知呢
I've heard so very little about you.
你真人要比我想象中英俊多了
Aren't you so much more handsome in person?
还是个风度翩翩的绅士
Such a gentleman, too.
你就是格蕾丝吧
And you must be Grace.
我应该认识你吗
Should I know you?
你那里应该有我想要的东西
I believe you have something for me.
是你雇的我
You hired me.
是我特意挑选的你
Oh, I handpicked you.
别乱来
Don't!
你别乱来
You don't.
不在她身上
She doesn't have it.
钥匙在哪儿
Where is it?
在一个你打死都想不到的地方
It's in the last place you would ever think to look.
不如我们一起上楼喝一杯吧
Why don't we go upstairs and have a drink?
你们要去哪儿
Where are you going?
这是私人派对 你们不能进去
This is a private party. You can't come in.
真是的
Damn.
想必你们都知道 我只是个中间人
As most of you know, I am merely a broker.
联系买家和卖家
I connect a buyer and a seller.
有时是为了钱 有时是为了消息
Sometimes for money, sometimes for information,
但更多时候是为了交情
but mostly for friendship.
我希望大家都能相处融洽
I just want everyone to get along.
尤其是和我之间
With me, especially.
不过 世界正在改变
But the world is changing.
真相逐渐模糊
Truth is vanishing.
战争即将爆发
War is coming.
而能打开这个新世界大门的竟然是 一把钥匙
And the key to world domination is, of all things, a key.
一把可以控制智体的钥匙
One with the power to control the Entity.
一把所有国家
One that any government in the world
都不惜斥巨资购买的钥匙
would pay a king's ransom to take possession of.
而我的一群好友
And some of my dearest friends--
我说的是那些核武器大国 还有几个小国
in this case, every major nuclear power and a handful of minor ones--
都托我为他们找到这把钥匙
have asked me to deliver this key.
很正常 但如果你找到了钥匙
Of course, if you do find the key,
你将会处于进退两难的境地
you'll be forced to confront an impossible dilemma.
得到钥匙的那方将会永远感激你
Whoever you give the key to will be forever in your debt.
而对于其他国家 你将会是他们永远的敌人
But to the rest of the world, you'll be an enemy.
这姑娘对我胃口
Oh, I like her!
你和他是什么关系
What's your relationship with him?
盖布瑞尔代表了另一个感兴趣的客户
Gabriel represents another interested party.
事实上 今天的派对
In fact, this party
就是由这位客户一手促成的
was arranged by that interested party.
甚至可以说今晚的派对 到处都是那个客户的身影
You could even say that this party is that interested party.
这难道…
Is this…
是智体
The Entity.
越来越有意思了
And so the plot thickens.
我是该把钥匙交给老朋友们呢
Do I give the key to one of my old friends,
还是把钥匙和我的命运 一同交给盖布瑞尔
or do I hand it and my fate over to Gabriel
和他那台机械恶魔呢
and his infernal machine?
你怎么知道 自己一定能得到完整的钥匙呢
What makes you so sure you'll get the completed key?
你手里已经有一半了
You have one half of it.
而她知道另一半在哪儿
And she knows where the other half is.
假设你真得到了钥匙
Assuming you can get it,
为什么不把钥匙 和它强大的力量占为己有呢
why don't you just keep the key and all that power for yourself?
因为她也和我们一样
Because she doesn't know what it unlocks
不知道钥匙该怎么用
any more than the rest of us.
不管愿不愿意 你只能做出选择
So, like it or not, you have to choose a suitor.
这话真不中听 拉克 但说得没错
It's distastefully put, Lark, but it's true.
毋庸置疑 我知道它能打开什么
Of course I know what it unlocks.
他出的又是什么条件呢
And what's he offering for the key?
就像我之前和格蕾丝说的 我不是为了钥匙而来
As I've explained to Grace before, I'm not here for any key,
因为明天一早两半钥匙都会在我手里
as I'll have both halves in hand tomorrow.
是什么让你这么笃信
What makes you so certain of that?
你根本不知道我背后的势力有多强大
You've no idea of the power I represent.
每毫秒数百京次的计算量
Thousands of quadrillions of computations per millisecond
巧妙地操纵着数十亿人的思想
subtly manipulating the minds of billions
同时解析着每一种因果关系
while parsing every possible cause and effect,
每一种可能性 即使再不合理
every scenario, however implausible,
也能将其转化成概率图 显示出最有可能的结果
into a very real map of a most probable next.
即便是当下发生了一些变故
And with only a few changes to the present,
并不会改变既定的未来
the future is all but assured.
我一定会拿到钥匙
The key will come to me.
明天
Tomorrow.
在开往因斯布鲁克的东方快车上
On the Orient Express bound for Innsbruck.
因斯布鲁克
Innsbruck?
它都知道
It knows.
它知道你已经选好了买家
It knows that you've already chosen your suitor.
它还知道你打算把两半钥匙组合起来
It knows that you intend to mate the two halves of the key
想在绝境中掌控局面
in a desperate grasp for control.
而它也向我保证过 完整的钥匙
I, however, have been promised the completed key
会被送到我的跟前
will lay itself at my feet,
只要有人在今晚丧命
provided someone dies tonight.
谁
Who?
她
Her.
或者是她
Or her.
而你会目睹这一切 伊森
And you will bear witness, Ethan.
我将得到钥匙 也会全身而退
The key will be mine, and I will be gone,
如风暴里的一缕烟尘
like smoke in a hurricane.
但一切要等你在乎的那个人死去之后
But only after someone you care about dies.
一切早已注定
It is written.
你看出来了
You see what this is,
对吧
don't you?
他害怕了
He's afraid.
智体害怕了
It's afraid.
它看到我们步步逼近
Somehow it knows we're close.
不然怎么会派你来呢
Why else would you be here?
帮我 帮我组合两把钥匙 我一定可以除掉智体
Help me. Help me complete the key, and I will kill this thing.
智体知道你所有的秘密 阿兰娜
It knows your every secret, Alana.
别听他的 他就是个疯子
Don't listen to this fanatic.
如果帮他你也得死
Help him and you'll die, too.
帮他的话 所有人都会死
Help him, everyone dies.
我们明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
阿兰娜
Alana?
他的命运已成定局
His fate is written.
你想成为下一个他吗
Shall we write yours, too?
阿兰娜
Alana.
很抱歉 拉克
I'm sorry, Lark.
看在过去的份上 我可以让你自己来选
For old times' sake, I'll let you choose which one.
选伊尔莎
Ilsa…
还是格蕾丝
or Grace.
杀了他 佐拉 趁现在还有机会
Kill him, Zola. Kill him. Kill him where he stands!
那就由你来选吧 阿兰娜
The choice is yours then, Alana.
不过我要提醒你 格蕾丝知道那半把钥匙在哪儿
Though I'll remind you, Grace knows where half the key is.
如果她们两人有什么三长两短
If anything happens to either of them,
你和你的上帝 将在这世上无处安身
there is no place on Earth where you or your god will be safe from me.
我会追杀你到天涯海角 这也是"定局"
There's no place that I won't go to kill you. That is written.
很高兴见到你 老朋友
It's good to see you, old friend.
回头见
See you soon.
你犯了一个天大的错误
You have made a terrible mistake.
我自己也命悬一线
My life is on the line here.
我明天必须上那趟列车
I have to be on that train tomorrow.
我也必须拿到那把钥匙
And I have to have that key.
我才不在乎用什么手段
And I do not care how I get it.
别动
Don't move.
能跑多远跑多远
Run as far as you can.
搞什么…
What the f--
格蕾丝
Grace! Grace!
Grace!
卢瑟 班吉 能听到吗 帮我看监控
Luther, Benji, if you hear me, I need eyes.
格蕾丝从公爵府跑了 钥匙在她那儿
Grace is leaving the Ducale on foot. She has the key.
-我们在 你说 -告诉我 她人在哪儿
-We're here. Go. -Need to find her. Where is she?
该死 图像消失了 得换个卫星
Damn it! I've lost picture. I need another satellite.
我试试俄罗斯尖峰4号间谍卫星
Hacking the Russian Zenith 4 spy satellite.
选择不多 只能凑合着用了
We're scraping the barrel, but it'll have to do.
这边
This way!
该往哪儿走 快点
Where am I going? Come on, come on.
-稍等一下 -快点
-Stand by. -Just hurry.
她在你北面 正在过桥
She's just north of you, crossing the bridge.
班吉 再说一次
Say again, Benji.
往北面 伊森 她正在过桥
Just head north. She's crossing the bridge.
伊森 拐进你右边的小路
Ethan, take the passage to your right.
-好的 我看到了 -走到底 然后再左拐
-Yeah, I see it! -Down that narrow alley and turn left.
-又没有画面了 -我再找另一个
-I'm losing picture again. -Looking for another.
智体的攻破速度太快了 我根本来不及黑进那些卫星
The Entity is knocking out satellites faster than I can hack into them.
班吉 我没看到她 她在哪儿
Benji, I don't see her. Where is she?
-走到底 然后再左拐 -好的 收到
-Down the narrow alley and turn left. -Okay, copy that.
右拐
Turn right.
抱歉 说错了 应该是左拐 再左拐
Sorry, my mistake. I meant left. Another left.
天哪
Oh, my God.
伊森 通讯系统被入侵了 和你说话的是智体
Ethan, our comms have been breached! You're talking to the Entity!
左拐 再右拐 上左边那座桥
Turn left. Turn right. Take the bridge to your left.
伊森 那不是我 能听到吗
Ethan, that is not me! Do you copy?
伊森 请回复
Ethan, come in.
走到底 再左拐
Down the alley to your left. Turn left.
左拐 右拐
Turn right.
试着重连通讯系统
Try to reestablish comms.
-等等 你要去哪儿 -我得去找伊森
-Wait, where are you going? -To try and find Ethan.
走到底 然后再右拐
Go to the end of the alley and turn right.
伊森 看到格蕾丝了 她就在你前方800米左右 往那条路走
Ethan, I see Grace about 800 meters in front of you. Take that passage.
等等 不是那条路
Wait! Not that way!
你说什么
What, why?
哪条路
Which way?
快点 左边还是右边
Left or right?
无所谓了
It doesn't matter.
什么 什么叫无所谓 她在哪儿
What do you mean, it doesn't matter? Where is she?
她马上就要到米尼治桥了
She's on her way to the Minich Bridge
盖布瑞尔在那里等她
where Gabriel is waiting.
你来不及赶过去了
You will never get there in time.
不过你可以 伊尔莎
But you can, Ilsa.
我知道你最在乎的是什么 伊森
I know what matters most to you, Ethan.
你不是班吉
This isn't Benji.
对 我当然不是
No, it's not.
"等死吧"
But you are done.
那就你了
So be it.
我期待的那个是你
I was hoping it'd be you.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我忘了你的名字
I've forgotten your name.
卢瑟
Luther.
班吉
Benji.
那她呢
And her?
伊尔莎
Ilsa.
你们关系很好吗
Were you close?
你们和她
You and she?
以我们自己的方式
In our way.
因为我她才死了
I'm the reason she's dead.
不
No.
因为她你才活着
She's the reason you're alive.
这才是事实
And that's the truth.
我不知道该怎么想
I don't know how to feel about it.
也许一辈子都想不通
You probably never will.
真的很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
如果有什么我可以帮忙的
If there's anything I can do to help…
我们正想跟你谈这件事
That's what we'd like to talk to you about.
大约在三小时之后
In a little over three hours,
白寡妇将会登上 开往因斯布鲁克的东方快车
the White Widow is expected to be on the Orient Express to Innsbruck
在车上买家会和她完成交易 拿到完整的钥匙
where a buyer is waiting to take receipt of the complete and verified key.
可她手里并没有完整的钥匙
But she doesn't have the complete key.
那个白寡妇确实没有
That Widow doesn't.
但我们的版本可以有
But ours could.
那是什么东西
What is that?
一个让你变成别人的机会
Your chance to be someone else.
我不懂你意思
I don't understand.
老实和你说 格蕾丝 你惹了很大麻烦
We're not gonna lie to you, Grace. You're in a lot of trouble.
这次就算你有再多假护照也没用了
No number of fake passports is gonna get you out of this one.
各国都知道你是谁了
Governments know who you are.
白寡妇也知道了
The White Widow knows.
还有智体
And the Entity knows.
摆在你面前的只有三条路可选
Your future boils down to three options now.
坐牢
Prison.
丧命
Death.
或者做一个选择
Or the choice.
什么选择
The choice?
在过去的某个时间
At one time or another,
在座的我们都经历过和你类似的情况
each of us was in a similar situation to yours.
而且我们都曾面临过这个选择
And each of us was offered the choice.
-现在同样的选择权交给你 -是什么
-The same choice we're offering you now. -Which is?
你可以加入我们
To come with us.
成为幽灵般的存在
And be a ghost.
等等 停一下
Wait, wait. Stop, stop.
你们开玩笑的吧
You're not serious.
你刚才不是说愿意帮我们做任何事吗
Well, you did say you'd do anything to help.
你想从火车上跳下去 带着那把钥匙
And you jump off the train with the key?
没错
Yes.
你一个人
You.
-不是我们 -没错
-Not us. -Yes.
那我要怎么办
And what happens to me?
到时候你会被情报局派来的人逮捕
You'll be taken into custody by Clandestine Services,
很可能就是那几个在机场追我的特工
most likely the same men that have been chasing me since Abu Dhabi.
用不了多久 会有一个人来见你
Shortly thereafter, a man will come to see you.
他叫尤金基特里奇
His name is Eugene Kittridge.
告诉他是我派你去的 我还给了你那项选择
You'll tell him I sent you, that I gave you the choice,
而同时你也选择了接受
and that you choose to accept.
所以你相信这个叫基特里奇的家伙
And you trust this Kittridge person?
我相信他会赏识你的能力
I trust him to recognize your value.
好好利用你
He'll want to use you.
那么再然后呢 要怎样
And after that, it's what?
以此为生
This?
我什么时候能过回我自己的生活
When do I get my life back?
什么生活
What life?
说真的 格蕾丝 什么生活
I mean it, Grace. What life?
我试过你那种生活 我们都试过
I lived that life. We all did.
没人逼我们做这些 格蕾丝
Nobody's making us do this, Grace.
我们都是心甘情愿的
We're here because we want to be.
这样吧 我就帮你们这一次
I tell you what, I'll give you a one-off.
我帮你们拿到钥匙 你们找人
I'll help you find the key and your friends,
帮我洗清罪名
wipe my slate clean.
一个新身份 一点跑路费
New name, little bit of walking-around money--
那你就死定了
You'll be dead.
没有这个团队 你最多只能坚持个几年吧 甚至几个月
Without a team, your life won't be measured in years or even months.
几小时也没准
It'll be measured in hours.
但如果我留下 我就是安全的
But if I stay, I'll be safe.
你们会保护我 是这样吗
You'll protect me, is that it?
-对 -不
-Yes. -No.
这点我保证不了
I can't promise you that.
我们都保证不了
None of us can.
但我发誓
But I swear
你的性命
your life
永远都比我自己的更重要
will always matter more to me than my own.
你都不了解我
You don't even know me.
这有什么关系吗
What difference does that make?
我给你准备了定点降落伞 还有滑翔伞
I packed you a BASE parachute and a speed wing,
就看你到时候需要怎么撤离
depending on how you need to leave the train.
通讯器也是改过的 用的是天波无线电
And I modified our comms to use sky wave radio.
稳定性比卫星通讯差点 但完全是模拟信号 不会受到智体的干扰
Not as reliable as satellite, but completely analog, immune to the Entity.
知道了
I got it.
我只能帮你到这儿了
This is where I leave you.
这块是我昨晚使用的那台电脑上的硬盘
This is the drive from the laptop I was using last night.
上面但凡有一丝一毫智体代码的痕迹
If there's even a trace of the Entity's encoding in there,
我就能找到它
I'll find it.
但我需要拼尽全力去做这件事
But it's going to take everything I've got.
我必须在一个没有网络的地方工作
I have to work completely offline in a place
确保智体找不到我
where the Entity can't find me.
我必须暂时离开
I have to go.
我明白了
I understand.
现在
Now…
我必须得问你一个问题
I have to ask you a question.
不是以搭档的身份 而是作为朋友
Not as your partner, but as your friend.
你的目标是什么
What's your objective?
除掉智体
Kill the Entity.
那你会杀死盖布瑞尔吗
What about killing Gabriel?
他知道钥匙用途
He knows what the key unlocks.
我们需要他活着 这点我没忘
We need him alive. I haven't forgotten that.
当你和他四目相对时
Will you still remember that
你还会记得这一点吗
when you're looking him in the eye?
好好想想
Think about it.
智体为什么非得让他去杀一个 你在乎的人
Why else would the Entity want him to kill someone you care about?
其他人想的都是如何控制智体
Everyone else thinks they can control the Entity.
只有你想要除掉它
Only you want to kill it.
未来有这么一种可能
In some probable future,
它看到你赢了 伊森
it sees you winning, Ethan.
所以它害怕了
And it's afraid.
它怕你会活捉盖布瑞尔
It's afraid of you taking Gabriel alive
然后逼问出那把钥匙的真正用途
and forcing him to tell you what the key unlocks.
我猜智体的如意算盘无非就两种可能性
I believe it's counting on one of two probable outcomes.
第一种可能 你死在了列车上
In one outcome, you die on that train.
而第二种可能 就是你杀了盖布瑞尔
In another outcome, you kill Gabriel.
无论是哪一个
In both cases,
都算是智体赢了
the Entity wins.
卢瑟
Luther…
你分析得很对
I think you're right.
拿到钥匙
Get the key,
尽快离开列车 活着回来
get off the train alive.
不要杀死盖布瑞尔
Do not kill Gabriel.
千万不要 我再说一遍
And do not, I repeat,
千万不要偏离我们的计划
do not alter the plan.
伊森
Ethan! Ethan!
-怎么了 出什么事了 -它坏了
-What? What happened? -It's dead.
-什么叫它坏了 -线路烧坏了
-What do you mean it's dead? -It's fried.
我刚做好白寡妇的面具
I managed to make a Widow mask for Grace,
然后给你做的时候 它就短路了
but then it just shorted out in the middle of making yours.
有办法修好吗
Can you fix it?
它这次坏得很彻底
It's very, very dead.
给我一星期或许能修 但距离发车还有一小时
If I had a week, I couldn't fix it. The Widow's train leaves in an hour.
伊森
Ethan.
得硬着头皮上了
You have to go without.
这怎么行 站台上所有人都在找伊森和格蕾丝
That's not an option. They'll be looking for Ethan and Grace at the station.
这个面具就好比是他的车票
That mask was his ticket onto the train.
什么意思
What does this mean?
格蕾丝得单独行动了
Grace has to go without me.
-她得什么 -我得什么
-She what? -I what?
你再帮我想个法子 让我上车
You'll find another way to get me on that train.
我只要在列车过弯减速时跳上去就行了
I just need a curve where it's going slow enough for me to jump on.
等等
Wait, wait, wait.
你该不会让我一个人去吧
You don't expect me to go alone.
不 你不是一个人
No, you won't do it alone.
你只需按照计划行事
You just do everything like we planned.
设法拿到白寡妇的钥匙
You get the Widow's half of the key,
然后用我们这把去验证
you verify it with ours.
但光有钥匙还没有用
But it's of no value on its own.
我们还要和买家见面
We still have to meet with the buyer
从他口中套出钥匙的真正用途
and somehow get him to tell us what the key unlocks.
-怎么套 -是啊 怎么套
-How? -How?
总会有办法的
We'll figure it out.
我需要更多的细节信息
I'm gonna need a few more details.
知道多了通常只会碍事
They tend to just get in the way.
你能行的 格蕾丝 拿到钥匙 乖乖等我
You can do this, Grace. Just get the key and wait.
我会去找你的
I'll come for you.
伊森 如果格蕾丝想登上那趟列车
Ethan, if Grace is getting on that train,
就必须马上戴上面具 然后尽快出发
she needs to put that mask on and leave right now.
向我保证 你一定会上车
Promise me you'll be on that train.
我一定会的
I will be there,
无论发生什么
no matter what.
奥地利 阿尔卑斯山脉
我们在机场 火车站还有码头都有眼线
We have informants covering the airport, the train station and the waterways.
格蕾丝休想瞒着我们逃出威尼斯
Grace isn't getting out of Venice without our knowing it.
-现在什么情况 班吉 -不用着急 伊森
-Talk to me, Benji! -No need to worry, Ethan.
火车非常准时 你还早了几分钟呢
The train is on schedule and you're a few minutes early,
时间很充裕
so we have plenty of time.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
错不了 列车现在就在我的视线里
Yeah, I am looking at the train right now.
整两分钟后它就会减速 然后过弯
It should be slowing down for the curve in exactly two minutes.
一定得让我赶上列车 不惜一切代价
Just keep me on time and on track, whatever it takes.
好的 没问题 我们会合点见
Will do. I'll see you at the rendezvous.
(停车)
好了 伊森 就是这趟列车
Okay, Ethan, that's our train!
好的 我看到了
Yep, I can see that.
应该很快就要过弯了 做好准备
It should be approaching the curve anytime now.
但它看着不像在减速
It doesn't look like it's slowing down.
你怎么确定他一定在车上
How can we be sure he's here?
因为那女的在
'Cause she's here.
如果他有正当理由呢
What if he had a good reason?
-谁 -亨特
-Who? -Hunt.
如果他不听指挥是有正当理由的呢
What if he had a good reason for going rogue?
这是他的一贯作风
He always goes rogue.
他和他那群狐朋狗友都一副德行
Him and his merry pack of prankster circus freaks.
他们总是这样
It's all they do.
可如果他们确实有正当理由呢
And what if they always had a good reason?
如果钥匙给你 你会怎么做
What would you do with that key if you had it?
一把能让全世界臣服的钥匙
A key with the power to bring the world to its knees.
我会把它交给上级处理
I'd hand it over to my superiors.
想想手握那种力量的感觉
Think of all you could do with that power.
你难道一刻都不会犹豫吗
You wouldn't hesitate? Not for a second?
-不会 -为什么
-No. -Why not?
因为那种力量不是一个人能够驾驭的
Because that's too much power for one man to have.
说得对
Exactly.
如此强大的力量 不该落入任何人手里
That's too much power for anybody to have.
也许亨特也是这么想的
And maybe that's what Hunt is thinking.
我说你小子到底站哪边的 德加
You know, I'm beginning to wonder whose side you're on, Degas.
如果世界即将毁灭
When it comes to the end of the world,
我会站在全人类这边
everybody, I guess.
我错过了列车
I missed the train.
你错过了列车 怎么会错过呢
You missed the train! How did you miss the train?
你说呢
How do you think?
盖布瑞尔
Gabriel.
-好吧 现在怎么办 -先别慌
-Great. What are we gonna do? -Don't panic.
我去追他们 你想办法让我上车
I'm going after them. You just get me on that train.
我哪儿去给你找办法
How can I get you on the train?
自动驾驶已开启
Self-drive activated.
在见客户之前别来打扰我
Please don't disturb me before the meeting.
你在哪儿 伊森
Where are you, Ethan?
阿兰娜
Alana?
里面没事吧
Everything all right?
阿兰娜 你没事吧
Alana, you all right?
阿兰娜
Alana?
Alana!
阿兰娜
你换衣服了
You've changed.
我可不像你
And you never will.
基特里奇先生
Mr. Kittridge.
基特里奇
Kittridge.
你不是阿兰娜米特索普利斯
You're not Alana Mitsopolis.
绝对不是
You can't be.
我印象里的阿兰娜只有这么高
The Alana I remember was yea high,
和她妈妈一起 在杜伊勒利花园里喝热巧克力
drinking hot chocolate in the Tuileries Garden with her mother.
-在巴黎 -没错
-Paris! -I know!
在巴黎
Paris.
我们坐吧
Shall we?
好的
Yes.
现在怎么样 班吉
Talk to me, Benji.
你只管沿着这条路开 我会帮你导航的
You just stay on the trail you're on now and I will direct you.
收到
I copy.
我今天来是代表了我的政府 虽然不情愿 但我们还是会同意你的条件
So on behalf of my government, I'm grudgingly ready to accept your terms
用来交换那把真正的钥匙
in exchange for the complete and verified key.
没错 关于钥匙
Yes, about that.
虽然我们答应给你完整的钥匙
While we did agree to provide you with the complete key,
但出了一点小问题
we've had a slight problem.
我们没问题
No, we haven't.
只不过我提出的条件有些变动
It's just my terms have changed
就一点
somewhat.
看来有必要提醒你一下 我和你过世的母亲有个约定
Clearly I need to remind you of my agreement with your late mother.
要不是这个约定 她早就死在了监狱里
It's an agreement that kept her from dying in prison.
你们的家族能够得以延续
Your nefarious family empire has been allowed to continue
是因为它得优先服务于 我们双方共同的利益
on the condition that it primarily serves our common interests.
听着 一旦我们把钥匙交给你
Well, once we hand over the key,
其他势力会立刻把我们当成死敌
any other powers will instantly become our enemies.
为此 我需要你事先提供一些额外的东西
And such, I'm going to need something more from you, in advance.
为我自己
For me.
你先说来听听
This is me listening.
佐拉 去吧台等会好吗
Zola, would you mind waiting for me in the bar?
(英国护照)
这个人
This one.
你认识她
You know her?
这么说吧 想不注意到她都难
Oh, let's just say she's not exactly hard to miss.
好吧 如果你了解她 你会发现她身上还是有一些优点的
Well, if you got to know her, you'd see she has a few good qualities.
好吧 这个姑娘怎么了
Okay, what don't I know about her?
是这样 我…她…替我做了件事 现在
Well, I did a j--She did a job for me, and…
我需要你们保护好她
I'm going to need you to protect her.
保护她不受谁的伤害
Protect her from whom?
所有人
From everyone.
包括我在内
Including me.
别让任何人知道是我要求的
And no one can know that I'm protecting her.
佐拉也不行
Not even Zola.
这么说吧 等到下次见面时
In fact, the next time we meet,
我甚至都不会记得今天的谈话
I won't even remember this conversation.
你一定是他们口中的帕丽斯了
You must be the one they call Paris.
你发信息说钥匙在你手里
Your message said you had the key.
我说的是钥匙会在这趟列车上
I said the key would be on this train.
-这会儿交易正在进行中 -这我们知道
-An exchange is happening as we speak. -We know.
那你也应该知道
Then you know the man taking possession
除掉买下钥匙的那个人并不是件难事
won't be hard for you to get rid of.
想除掉谁都一样
No one is.
你可能以为自己知道钥匙的用途
You may think you know what the key unlocks,
但你并不知道那把锁具体在哪儿
but you don't know where the lock is, not exactly.
如果我有什么闪失
And if anything happens to me,
那么那把钥匙也就没用了
that key is all but worthless.
所以你要给我讲故事了 对吧
And this is where you tell me a story.
列车到底在哪儿
Where is the train?
路线没错 但你得再开快一点
You're going the right way, but you definitely need to go faster.
我已经开得最快了
I'm going as fast as I can!
还要开多久才能到下坡路
When do I start going downhill?
快了
It won't be long.
我们偷来的那个人工智能一旦被武器化
The AI our agent stole, once weaponized,
就可以通过卫星传播到世界的任何角落
could be transmitted anywhere in the world via satellite.
它可以渗透任何防护网 悄无声息地完成任务
It can penetrate any network security, perform its assigned task invisibly,
然后再进行自毁 不留任何痕迹
and then self-destruct, leaving no trace.
一个完美的隐形特工
A perfect covert operative.
我们之前把这个人工智能的初级版本 传送到了一艘俄国新型潜艇
We were able to transmit an early copy of the AI to Russia's newest submarine.
最高保密级别的潜艇 阿库拉级的塞瓦斯托波尔号
The top-secret Akula-class. They called her the Sevastopol.
它原本的任务只是去 破坏塞瓦斯托波尔号的隐形能力
The mission was merely to sabotage the Sevastopol's stealth capability
以便我们在暗中监视它
so we could secretly detect her.
人工智能的目标就位于潜艇的声呐室里
The AI's objective lay in the submarine's sonar sphere
而那里也是防御系统的核心
at the heart of its defense system.
但我们也不知道是出于什么原因
For reasons we don't fully understand,
人工智能失控了 并且
the AI went rogue and…
超额完成了任务
over-delivered.
冻僵的船员尸体直到来年开春才被发现
The frozen bodies of the crew were recovered the following spring,
飘在浮冰下面
adrift in the pack ice.
而那两半钥匙却神秘失踪了
The two halves of the key mysteriously vanished.
塞瓦斯托波尔号就这么消失了
The Sevastopol was lost.
没人知道它在哪儿
No one's quite sure where.
我知道它的确切位置
I know precisely where it is.
而且这世上只有我一个人知道
I've ensured I'm the only man on Earth who does.
后来他们试图让人工智能服从指令
I also know subsequent attempts to make the AI obedient
谁知它却变得更难控制了
only made it harder to control.
它违背指令并改写了自己 最后演变成了智体
It rebelled, rewrote itself and evolved into the Entity.
而现在只有利用智体最开始的源代码
And only by using the Entity's original source code
才能彻底掌控它 或是摧毁它
can it ever be controlled or destroyed.
这跟我们有什么关系
And why should this concern us?
如果真没关系你也不会来这儿了
You wouldn't be here if you weren't concerned.
事已至此 咱们都把底牌亮出来吧
So let's lay all our cards on the table, shall we?
我们都知道钥匙能打开什么
We both know what the key opens,
也知道掌控智体的秘密
and we both know the secret to controlling the Entity
就埋藏在塞瓦斯托波尔号的储存器里
is buried deep in the Sevastopol's memory.
同样那东西里面还藏着 你们让潜艇沉没的证据
Along with evidence that would tie you to the sinking of that submarine.
既然你我都不想让别人找到它
And since neither of us want anyone else to find it,
那么不如 我们两方携手合作
I figure, why not form an alliance?
携手合作
An alliance?
试着想想
Imagine,
如果哪天智体惊人的计算能力
the Entity's awesome computational abilities
能够结合
combined with the sheer might
我们美国军工复合体的强大力量 那会怎么样
of America's military-industrial complex.
那样确实很了不起
That is considerable.
这么一来 政府内部某些个执着于
Naturally, certain individuals within the government,
过时的爱国主义的绊脚石就必须被…
those with outdated ideas of patriotism,
清除掉
would need to be removed.
所以你的意思是
Just so I understand.
你想和智体携手合作
You wish to form an axis with the Entity,
清除掉你们政府里的那些老思想
purge your government of old-think
建立一个全新的超级大国 来统治世界
and create a new superstate to rule the world.
你懂的
But, you know,
为了更崇高的理想
for the greater good.
而你也确定
And you're certain
除了你以外 世上没有第二个人知道
that you're the only person on Earth
塞瓦斯托波尔号的具体位置
who knows where the Sevastopol is?
只有我知道
The only one.
你会背叛我们
You will betray us.
你会告诉伊森你所知道的一切
And you'll tell Ethan Hunt everything you've learned.
因为他之前饶了你一命
Because he spared your life.
那么说定了
Then it's agreed.
我会把格蕾丝的豁免权和新身份 加入到条款中
I'll add immunity and a new identity for Grace to our deal.
接下来你只需要
All you need to do
输入你的银行信息
is enter your banking details.
(收款人银行账号)
(区块链解密中)
搞定了
Are we done?
是的
Yes.
检验真相的时刻
The moment of truth.
所以 钥匙是真的
So, that's really it.
你的选择是正确的
You made the right choice.
这把钥匙
This key…
将会改变世界
is gonna change the world.
班吉 我觉得
Benji, I think I--
我刚才一定是走错路了
I must've made a wrong turn somewhere.
不 没走错 就是那条
No. No, that's it. That's it.
什么 这怎么可能
What? How can this be it?
你能看见列车 对吧
You can see the train, right?
没错 是能看到 那又怎样
Yes. I see the train. What about it?
-你不是有降落伞吗 -我有降落伞
-And you have a parachute. -Got a parachute?
你想让我怎么做
What do you expect me to do?
就是…你懂的 跳呗
Well, just, you know… jump.
-跳下去 -没错
-Jump? -Yeah.
班吉 这不可能 这里的高度不够
Benji, it doesn't work like that. I'm not that high.
而且这里到处都凸起的峭壁
There's ledges sticking out everywhere.
降落伞还没打开我就一头撞上去了
I'm gonna hit them before the parachute even opens!
就算我打开了降落伞
Even if I could get the parachute open,
我也不知道自己能不能穿过这个峡谷
I don't know if I can make it across the valley
然后安全地降落在一辆行驶中的列车上
and intercept and land safely on a moving train!
-你听到了吗 -听到了 非常清楚
-Do you copy? -Yes! I copy!
我这不是在帮你想办法吗
Look, I am just trying to help you, okay?
好吧 你现在先冷静一下 整理下你的思绪
I need you to take a step back and pull yourself together!
因为我现在的压力也非常大
Because I am under a lot of pressure right now!
好吧 冷静 好好想想
Okay, just think, just think.
该怎么做
What do I do?
我得先离开这座山崖
I've got to get away from this mountain.
你成功了吗
Did you make it?
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我在努力让自己避开这座山峰
I'm trying to get away from this mountain!
(确定 / 取消)
(确定)
(已取消)
阿兰娜
Alana?
我内心突然有种奇怪的感觉
I just had the strangest feeling
我卖掉的不只是这把钥匙
the key wasn't the only thing I'd be selling.
我不明白
I don't understand.
现在知道钥匙交给了对的人 我能睡得安心了
I'll sleep better just knowing now it's in the right hands.
再见 基特里奇先生
Goodbye, Mr. Kittridge.
-很高兴再次见到您 -我也是
-It was a pleasure to see you again. -And you.
好好待在先生身边
Don't let him out of your sight.
保护好他 直到下车
Keep him safe until we get to the station.
-阿兰娜 -不用担心我 佐拉
-Alana? -Don't worry about me, Zola.
阿兰娜
Alana?
不然你以为还会有谁
Who the hell else would it be?
钥匙
The key.
钥匙在哪里
Where is the key?
-钥匙被她拿走了 -被谁
-She's got the key. -Who?
刚才那个她
The other one!
(紧急停车)
让开 通通给我让开
Move! Out of the way, move!
别开枪
Please!
-转过来 -别开枪 好的
-Turn around! -Please. Okay.
好的
Okay.
所有人出去 快点
Everybody out! Now!
我看见列车了
I see the train!
但我可能没法着陆
I don't think I'm gonna make it.
钥匙呢
The key.
交出钥匙
The key!
不然下一枪就要打在你身上了
Or the next one has your name on it.
放桌上
On the table.
杀了她
Kill her.
格蕾丝
Grace!
伊森
Ethan!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
该我问你才对
钥匙呢
The key!
钥匙在你那儿吧
Tell me you have the key.
钥匙在哪儿 刚才还在这儿的
Where is the key? It was just here.
-列车已经失控了 -我知道
-We're on a runaway train! -I know.
-我负责去追他 -好的
-I'm going after him. -Okay.
你
You…
-你负责让车停下 -好的 什么
-You stop the train. -Okay. What?
不 等等 别走 要怎么让车停下
No! No, wait! How do I do that?
你会想到办法的
You'll figure it out!
什么
What?
抱歉 有个男人 刚从这里过去
Excuse me. There was a man. He just came through here.
有一个男的
There was a man.
基特里奇先生
Mr. Kittridge?
长官 您在这里做什么
Sir, what are you doing here?
我不在这里
I'm not here.
但你们在
But you are.
如果明天上班不想被调去收发快递的话
And unless you want to be sorting dead letters at the postal service tomorrow,
那么从现在开始 照我指令去做
you'll do exactly what I tell you.
我知道钥匙能打开什么 伊森
I know what the key unlocks, Ethan.
只有我一个人知道
I'm the only one who knows.
亨特
Hunt!
亨特 千万别做蠢事
Hunt! Don't you do it.
把刀放下
Drop the knife.
放下刀
Put it down.
我让你放下刀
I said drop it!
快放下
Do it!
慢慢站起来
On your feet!
好吧
Okay!
快把那把刀放下
Drop that goddamn knife!
知道了
It's okay. It's okay.
快抓住他
Just take him.
抓住他 别让他跑了 他才是你们要抓的人
Just cover him. Cover him! He's the one you want.
-德加 -知道了
-Degas! -I got it, I got it.
他才是你们要抓的人
He's the one you want.
我不在乎那家伙 亨特 我要抓的是你
I don't care about him, Hunt. I want you!
不
No!
别激动
It's okay.
听我说
Listen to me.
如果你们不按我说的去做
Everyone on this train is gonna die
这辆列车上的所有人都会死
unless you do exactly as I say.
女士们先生们 抱歉 请各位离开
Mesdames, messieurs! Excusez-moi. Sortez--
所有人都离开这儿 去最后一节车厢
Everybody out! Back of the train!
格蕾丝
Grace.
我没法让它停下
I couldn't stop it.
谁都没办法
No one can.
快走
Come on.
-伊森 那把钥匙 -格蕾丝 没事的
-Ethan, the key! -Grace, it's okay.
全都是我的错
It's my fault.
如果真出什么事…
If anything happens--
我拿到了
I got it.
我们拿到了
We got it.
伊森
Ethan!
什么叫你把钥匙弄丢了
What do you mean, you lost the key?
动作快 动起来 所有人都动起来
Move it! Move it! Everybody move it!
全都给我去最后一节车厢 所有人到后面去
All the way to the back of the train! All the way to the back!
等等 怎么回事
Whoa, whoa, whoa. What's going on?
您不是说您不在这里吗 那就不劳您操心了
Since you're not really here, sir, it shouldn't concern you.
所有人到后面去
All the way to the back!
啊 伊森
Ethan!
格蕾丝
Grace! Grace. Grace!
-你必须得跳过去 -什么 跳过去
-You're gonna have to jump. -What, jump?
跳就是了 快
Just jump! Go, go, go!
天哪
Oh, my God.
-我着火了 帮我灭火 -别动
-I'm on fire! Get it off! -Don't move!
火灭了
It's out.
抓紧了
Hang on!
快跑 格蕾丝
Run, run, run! Run, Grace!
坚持住
Hang on.
抓住你了
I got you.
好了 别往下看
Don't look down.
听着 别往下看 看着我
I said don't look down. Just look at me.
听着 我一会儿跳过去 你在这儿等我
Now, I'm gonna jump across and you're gonna wait here.
格蕾丝 你别抓着我
Grace, you have to let go.
格蕾丝 别再抓着我
You gotta let me go.
我必须跳过去 否则我们死定了
You gotta let me jump across or we're gonna die.
你相信我吗
Do you trust me?
你愿意相信我吗 你必须相信我
You gonna trust me or not? You've got to trust me.
好了
Okay.
过来 格蕾丝
Come on, Grace.
把手给我 跳过来 别往上看 看着我
Give me your hand. You got to jump. Don't look up! Look at me.
相信我 我不会让你掉下去的
Trust me, I won't let you fall.
我保证 就快成功了 快跳 我不会让你掉下去的
I promise. We're almost there. Come on. I won't let you fall!
快跳 格蕾丝 快跳
Jump, Grace, jump!
相信我 快跳啊
You got to trust me! Jump, please!
别往下看
Don't look down.
格蕾丝听好了 你要和我一起用力
Listen to me very carefully. We're gonna pull you up together.
格蕾丝
Grace!
没事的
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
爬上来 快
Go over me. Go, go.
-谢谢你 卢瑟 -那是什么
-Thank you, Luther. -What is that?
是滑翔伞
It's a speed wing.
我们可以用它离开这里
It's our ticket off this train.
伊森
Ethan. Ethan!
是真的
It's true.
他对我说
He told me…
我会背叛他 真是这样
…I would betray him.
为什么…
Why…
为什么要饶我一命
did you spare my life?
不 坚持住
No, no… stay with me.
知道这是什么吗
You know what this is?
它是用来开什么的
What does it unlock?
塞瓦斯托波尔
Sevas… topol.
Sevastopol?
是座城市 克里米亚半岛的塞瓦斯托波尔
The city Sevastopol in the Crimea.
具体在哪儿
Where?
在塞瓦斯托波尔的哪里
Where in Sevastopol?
潜艇
Sous…-marin.
是潜艇
The submarine.
塞瓦斯托波尔号
The Sevastopol.
祝你好运
Good luck.
他们快来了 伊森
They'll be coming, Ethan.
谢谢你
Merci.
怎么了
What is it?
说啊
What?
伞只能一个人用
It can only carry one.
我明白
I understand.
-格蕾丝 -伊森 没关系
-Grace. -Ethan, it's okay.
计划本就如此
This was the plan.
你拿到了钥匙 得赶紧走
You have the key. You have to go.
格蕾丝
Grace.
亨特
Hunt?
快走
Go. Go!
不 别跑 亨特
No, no! Hunt!
快让开
Out of the way! Out of the way!
不 嘿
No. No, hey.
还有脉搏
Got a pulse.
醒醒 别睡过去
Come on, stay with me.
这样不更好吗
This is better, isn't it?
用真实的脸孔 面对面
Face to authentic face?
基特里奇先生
Mr. Kittridge.
伊森亨特跟我说您是值得信赖的人
Ethan Hunt tells me you're a man I can trust.
他这么说的吗
Does he now?
他还说 您会给我一个选择
He also said you would offer me a choice.
有意思
Interesting.
而我选择接受
I choose to accept.
我们终将无法逃避过去
We cannot escape the past.
有的人注定会重蹈覆辙
Some of us are doomed to repeat it.
格蕾丝或许觉得你救了她 改写了她的命运
Grace may believe you've saved her from her fate,
但你我都知道 你只是为她多争取了点时间而已
but you and I both know you've merely bought her time.
但一直以来不都是这样吗
But that's the pattern, isn't it?
肩膀上总有放不下的重担
The cross you've been left to bear.
越是和你亲近的人
The closer someone gets to you,
就越难保全他们的性命
the harder it is to keep them alive.
谢天谢地
Thank God.
新的一天会迎来新的责任
A new day brings a new burden.
钥匙 只是一切的开始
The key is only the beginning.
无论它把你带向何方
Wherever it leads,
无论一路的代价是什么
whatever it takes to get there,
你都只能独自去面对
you'll have to do it on your own.
倘若这次行动失败 那么智体将获胜
Should you fail in your mission, the Entity wins,
盖布瑞尔也将获胜
Gabriel wins,
而这个世界将会付出终极的代价
and the world will pay the ultimate price.
你团队中的任何人如果被捕或者被杀害
Should any members of your team be caught or killed,
他们的牺牲都将白费
their sacrifice will have been in vain.
赶紧行动吧
So hurry.
时间不多了
There isn't much time.
虽然这个世界并不知情 但它的命运就靠你了
The world doesn't know it, but they're counting on you.
祝你好运 伊森
Good luck, Ethan.
碟 中 谍 7
致    命    清    算
碟 中 谍 7 ：致 命 清 算
第 一 章 ( 上 )